<book>
<nid>
<type>node_id</type>
<value>152</value>
</nid>
<title>
<type>node_title</type>
<value>Edoovillage Request Form</value>
</title>
<field_book_language>
<type>value</type>
<value>English</value>
</field_book_language>
<field_is_first_page>
<type>value</type>
<value>1</value>
</field_is_first_page>
<field_reference_book>
<type>target_id</type>
<value>152</value>
</field_reference_book>
<body>
<type>value</type>
<value><strong>English Version</strong>

--------------------------------
Requester Information:
--------------------------------
Your Name:
Your Email Address:
Your Organization :
Organization Website:
You Labdoo account user name: (this is needed so that Labdoo can assign laptops to your project--registration can be done here: https://www.labdoo.org/user/register)
Project title: (a short title for your project)

-----------------
Project Site:
-----------------
1.  Project Summary: (Please provide a brief statement about the purpose that the laptops will serve in your project site.)
2.  Project Location:
3.  Preferred language(s):
4.  On Site Contact Information (please provide at least one way to contact):
    4.1. Name:
    4.2. Phone:
    4.3. Email:
    4.4. Physical address (street, city, zip code, country...):
    4.5. GPS coordinates (if you know them or if you can find them out):
5.  Claimed IT equipement
    Number of Laptops needed:
    Number of eBook Reader needed:
    Others needed (Tablet-PCs etc):
6.  Number of students:
7.  Number of teachers:
8.  Electricity in the room: (Voltage and plug/socket type, e.g. type A, B, C, D, etc. see following link for explanation of types: http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/AC_power_plugs_and_sockets)
9.  Does the room have access to the Internet? [yes / no]
    9.1. Is the access via wireless or cable?
10. Conditions about the room where the laptops will be installed:
    10.1. Is the room secure? [yes / no + brief explanation]
    10.2. Can the room be locked in a way that the supervisors (e.g. teachers) can control access? [yes / no + brief explanation]
    10.3. Is the room weather-proof? (e.g. does the room protect the laptops from rain, sand, etc?) [yes / no + brief explanation]

***The solicitation of a Labdoo laptop request implies that, upon receiving the laptops, the recipient agrees with the "Labdoo Laptop Recipient Agreement".

----------------------------------------------------
Labdoo Laptop Recipient Agreement:
----------------------------------------------------

Dear Laptop receiver:

We are very pleased to have the opportunity to contribute to your project by providing technology to help bridge the digital divide.
With every right comes responsibilities. Technology, when adequately used, can provide very powerful means to aid those that are
most in need. But if used improperly, it can also damage our environment. By receiving the above items, you are automatically a
ccepting to abide by the following Labdoo global responsibilities:

(1) The items received will be used only for the purpose described by your organization at the time you solicited this donation.
If you intend to use it for a different purpose, you will contact first the Labdoo team at contact@labdoo.org.

(2) In the case that an incidence occurs to any of the received items, you will contact the Labdoo team at contact@labdoo.org,
including in your email the tagging number of the item(s) related to the incidence and a brief explanation. The following
incidences must always be reported:
        (2.1) At the end of life of any of the received items, so that the item can be properly recycled.
        (2.2) When an item breaks, malfunctions or any change in its status.

(3) Every six months, please send an email to contact@labdoo.org with the list of laptops that you have and their status (working or not working).

(4) Labdoo laptops are offered for free to you for education purposes.  In return, you agree to not use the laptops for commercial
reasons and you agree not to charge any fee for the usage of the laptops.

(5) By returning this form filled in, the solicitor confirms owning all rights on sent materials (current or in the future) submitted to Labdoo.org and allowing such content to be publicly available from Labdoo.org. In addition, the solicitor confirms having approval for taking pictures of the children and/or any person benefiting from Labdoo laptops, tablets or any Labdoo donations, from their parents and/or legal guardians. Labdoo.org explicitly points to the fact that sent materials and pictures/photos may be used online and/or offline, and hence that they can be accessed by third parties, and that such pictures are used to help preserve the transparency and accountability of the projects.

We thank you for your commitment to make our world a better place and we wish you best of luck in your humanitarian mission.

The Labdoo Team.

<strong>Catalan Version</strong>

Formulari de sol·licitud Labdoo


Informació del sol·licitant:
======================
El teu nom:
La teva a/e:
La teva organització:
La web de l'organització:
El nom d'usuari del teu compte Labdoo: (això és necessari per tal de que Labdoo pugui assignar els portàtils al teu projecte, el registre es pot fe aquí: https://www.labdoo.org/user/register)
Títol del projecte: (un breu títol del teu projecte)


Lloc del projecte:
=============
1. Resum del projecte: (Si us plau, escriu una breu descripció sobre l'ús que li donaràs als portàtils en el teu lloc del projecte).
2. Lloc del projecte:
3. Llenguatge/s preferit/s:
4. Informació de contacte del lloc (si us plau, com a mínim escriu una forma de contacte):
    4.1. Nom:
    4.2. Telèfon:
    4.3. A/e:
    4.4. Adreça física (carrer, ciutat, CP, país, ...):
    4.5. Coordinades GPS (si les coneixes o si pots trobar-les):
5. Nombre de portàtils necessaris:
6. Nombre d'estudiants:
7. Nombre de professors:
8. Electricitat a l'habitació: (Voltatge i tipus de connectors a la paret, p. ex. tipus A, B, C, D, etc. mira el següent enllaç per més explicacions dels tipus: http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/AC_power_plugs_and_sockets)
9. L'habitació té accés a Internet? [sí / no]
    9.1. L'accés és via sense fils o amb cable?
10. Condicions sobre l'habitació on els portàtils poden ser instal·lats:
    10.1. L'habitació és segura? [sí / no + breu explicació]
    10.2. L'habitació pot ser tancada per tal que els supervisors (p. ex. els professors) puguin controlar l'accés? [sí / no + breu explicació]
    10.3. L'habitació és resistent a l'aigua? (p. ex. l'habitació protegeix els portàtils de la pluja, sorra, etc.?) [sí / no + breu explicació]


***La sol·licitud de petició d'un portàtil Labdoo implica que, un cop rebuts el/s portàtil/s, el sol·licitant està d'acord amb les condicions d'ús de Labdoo.

Condicions d'ús de Labdoo:
====================================
Estimat/da beneficiari/a del/s portàtil/s:

Ens plau moltíssim tenir l'oportunitat de contribuir al seu projecte proveint tecnologia que ajuda a reduir la fractura digital.

Però tot dret comporta responsabilitats. La tecnologia, quan s'utilitza adequadament, pot proporcionar mitjans molt poderosos per ajudar a aquells que més ho necessiten. Però si s'utilitza de forma inadequada, també pot malmetre el medi ambient. En rebre els elements anteriors, automàticament accepta complir amb les següents responsabilitats globals de Labdoo:

(1) Els elements rebuts seran utilitzats només pels propòsits descrits per la seva organització el dia que va sol·licitar la donació. Si vol utilitzar-los per a altres propòsits, haurà de contactar primer amb l'equip Labdoo a: contact@labdoo.org.

(2) En cas que passi un incident amb qualsevol dels elements rebuts, contactarà amb l'equip Labdoo a contact@labdoo.org, incloent en el correu electrònic el número d'etiquetat de/dels l'element/s relacionats amb la incidència i una breu explicació. Les següents incidències sempre han de ser informades:
	(2.1) El final del cicle de vida de l'element rebut, per tal que els elements puguin ser reciclats.
	(2.2) Quan algun element es trenca, no funciona correctament o hi ha qualsevol canvi en el seu estat.
Un portàtil trencat pot ser molt perjudicial per al medi ambient i, per tant, els beneficiaris hauran de comunicar aquest tipus d'incidències al sistema/comunitat de Labdoo, per tal d'assegurar el seu correcte reciclatge.

(3) Cada sis mesos, si us plau, enviï un correu electrònic a contact@labdoo.org amb la llista dels ordinadors portàtils que té i el seu estat (funciona o no funciona).

Li agraïm el seu compromís en fer del món un lloc millor i li desitgem molta sort en la seva missió humanitària.

L'Equip Labdoo.

<strong>Chinese Version</strong>

Labdoo筆記型電腦申請表


申請者資料：
======================
您的姓名： 
您的電子郵件地址： 
您的組織名稱： 
組織網站： 

個案地點：
=============
1. 個案摘要： （請提供一個簡短的說明, 關於申請筆記型電腦的目的及用途。）
2. 個案地點： 
3. 個案當地聯絡人： 
4. 聯絡方式（請至少提供一個聯絡方式）：
    4.1. 電話： 
    4.2. 電子郵件： 
    4.3. 實際地址： 
      
5. 所需的筆記型電腦數量： 
6. 學生人數： 
7. 教師人數： 
8. 教室內的電力：C型（電壓和插頭 /插座的類型，如A型，B，C，D等，請參閱以下鏈接類型的說明：http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/AC_power_plugs_and_sockets）

9. 教室是否可上網嗎? [是/否] 
    9.1. 透過過無線或有線連線?如果未來要上網的話，需使用無線上網方式
10. 預計安裝筆記型電腦所在教室的條件：
    10.1. 教室安全嗎？ [是/否+簡要說明] 
    10.2. 教室能上鎖, 並可由管理者（如教師）控制電腦的使用嗎? [是/否+簡要說明] 
    。
    10.3. 教室能防風雨嗎? （如教室能保護筆記型電腦免受雨淋，沙塵損壞?）[是/否+簡要說明] 


***驗收後，申請者將需要閱讀與同意“Labdoo筆記本收件人協議”

<strong>French Version</strong>

Formulaire de demande d’ordinateur portable Labdoo 

Information du demandeur
Votre nom :
Votre adresse email :
Votre organisation :
Site WEB de votre organisation :
Votre nom d’utilisateur de votre compte Labdoo : (C’est nécessaire pour que Labdoo puisse assigner des portables à votre projet – Vous pouvez vous inscrire ici : https://www.labdoo.org/user/register)
Titre du projet : (un titre court pour votre projet)


Site du projet
1. Résumé du projet : (Décrivez brièvement l’usage qu’il sera fait des ordinateurs portables sur le site de votre projet)
2. Emplacement du projet :
3. langue(s) préférée(s) :
4. Information de contact sur le site (fournissez au moins un moyen de contact)
a. Nom
b. Téléphone
c. Email
d. Adresse physique (Rue, Ville, Code postal, pays…) :
e. Coordonnées GPS (Si vous les connaissez ou si vous avez un moyen de les trouver)
5. Nombre d’ordinateurs dont vous avez besoin :
6. Nombre d’étudiants :
7. Nombre d’enseignants :
8. Electricité dans la pièce : (Voltage et type de prise, par exemple type A, B, C, D, etc. Consultez les explications des types de prise sur le lien suivant http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/AC_power_plugs_and_sockets)
9. Avez-vous accès à Internet dans la pièce ? [Oui / Non]
a. Est-ce un accès sans-fil ou par cable ?
10. Conditions sur la pièce où les portables seront installés
a. La pièce est-elle sécurisée [Oui / Non + explication brève]
b. La pièce peut-elle être fermée de telle façon que les superviseurs (par exemple les enseignants) puissent en contrôler l’accès ? [Oui / Non + explication brève]
c. La pièce est-elle à l’abri des intempéries ? (par exemple la pièce peut-elle protéger les ordinateurs de la pluie, du sable etc. ?) [Oui / Non + explication brève]

*** La demande d’ordinateurs Labdoo implique que le destinataire accepte « l’accord de destinataire de portable Labdoo » (Labdoo Laptop Recipient Agreement) à la réception des ordinateurs portables. 


Accord de destinataire de portable Labdoo :

Cher receveur de portable :

Nous sommes très heureux d’avoir l’opportunité de contribuer à votre projet en vous fournissant la technologie qui aide à combler la brêche numérique.
Avec chaque droit viennent les responsabilités. La technologie, lorsqu’elle est correctement utilisée, peut fournir les moyens d’aider ceux qui en ont le plus besoin. Mais si elle est utilisée incorrectement, elle peut aussi causer des dégâts à notre environnement. En recevant les articles ci-dessus, vous acceptez automatiquement de respecter les responsabilités globales de Labdoo suivantes :

(1) Les articles reçus ne seront utilisées que pour les objectifs décrits par votre organisation lorsque vous avez sollicité ce don. Si vous avez l’intention de les utiliser pour des objectifs différents, vous devez d’abord contacter l’équipe Labdoo à contact@labdoo.org   
(2) Si un problème se présente avec l’un des articles reçus, vous devez d’abord contacter l’équipe Labdoo à contact@labdoo.org, en mentionnant dans votre email le numéro de l’étiquette de l’article et une brève description. Vous devez toujours reporter les évênements suivants : 
a. A la fin de vie de tout article reçu, afin qu’il puisse être correctement recyclé
b. Lorsque un article est cassé ou ne fonctionne plus correctement ainsi que tout changement dans son état.
(3) Tous les six mois, vous devez envoyer un email a contact@labdoo.org avec (la liste des ordinateurs portables en votre possession et leur état (fonctionnent ou ne fonctionnent pas). 

Nous vous remercions pour votre engagement à faire du monde un endroit meilleur et nous vous souhaitons bonne chance dans votre mission humanitaire.

L’équipe Labdoo 

<strong> German Version</strong>

Labdoo Laptop Antragsformular
Rev.  001

Informationen zum Antragssteller:
================================
Dein Name:
Deine Email Adresse:
Deine Organisation :
Website der Organisation:
Dein Labdoo Konto User Name: (dieser wird benötigt, damit Labdoo Laptops deinem Projekt zuweisen kann--Die Registrierung kann hier erfolgen: https://www.labdoo.org/user/register)
Project title: (ein kurzer Titel für dein projekt, am besten -> Land, Region/Ort: Name der Schule)

Projektinformationen:
====================
1.  Projektbeschreibung: (Bitte beschreibe hier kurz, wie die Laptops in deinem projekt zum Einsatz kommen sollen.)
2.  Projektort:
3.  Bevorzugte Sprache(n):
4.  Vor Ort Kontakt (bitte nenne wenigstens einen Weg zur Kontaktaufnahme):
    4.1. Name: 
    4.2. Telefon:
    4.3. Email:
    4.4. Physikalische Adresse (Straße, Stadt, PLZ, Land, ...):
    4.5. GPS Koordinaten (wenn du sie kennst oder herausfinden kannst):
5.  Beantragt werden 
    Anzahl benötigter Computer:
    (Inlandsprojekte erhalten PCs, Auslandsprojekte Laptops)
    Anzahl benötigter eBook Reader: 
    Sonstiges (Tablet-PCs o.a.): 
6.  Anzahl Schüler:
7.  Anzahl Lehrer:
8.  Stromversorgung in der Schule: (Stromspannung und Art des Steckers, z.B. Typ A, B, C, D, etc. Siehe folgenden Link zur Erklärung der Typen http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/AC_power_plugs_and_sockets)
9.  Hat der Raum Zugang zum Internet? [ja / nein]
    9.1. Ist der Zuganng via WLAN oder LAN-Kabel?
10. Zustand der Räume, in denen die Laptops installiert werden:
    10.1. Ist der Raum sicher? [ja / nein + kurze Erläuterung]
    10.2. Kann der Raum durch die Lehrer abgeschlossen werden, um den Zugang zu kontrollieren? [ja / nein + kurze Erläuterung]
    10.3. Ist der Raum wettergeschützt? (z.B. sind die Laptops im Raum vor Sand und Regen sicher?) [ja / nein + kurze Erläuterung]

*** Mit dem Abruf und dem Empfang von Labdoo Laptops verpflichtet sich der Empfänger zur Einhaltung der "Labdoo Laptop Empfänger Vereinbarung".

Labdoo Laptop Vereinbarung mit dem Empfänger:
============================================

Lieber Laptop Empfänger:

Wir freuen uns über die Möglichkeit, Ihr Projekt durch die Bereitstellung von IT-Technologie bei der Überwindung des "digitalen Grabens" zu unterstützen.
Mit jeder Laptopspende kommt aber auch eine Verantwortung. Richtig genutzte Technologie ist ein wirksames Mittel, diejenigen zu unterstützen, die Hilfe am dringendsten benötigen. Aber falsch eingesetzte Technik kann auch der Umwelt schaden. Mit Antragstellung und Erhalt der Laptops akzeptieren Sie automatisch die folgenden Punkte:

(1) Die IT-Spenden werden ausschließlich für die Zwecke Ihrer Organisation genutzt, wie im o.a. Antrag beschrieben. Wenn Sie sie doch für einen anderen Zweck verwenden wollen, müssen Sie zuerst beim Labdoo anfragen: contact@labdoo.org.
(2) Wenn es zu einer Störung oder Fehlfunktion bei den gespendeten IT-Teilen kommt kontaktieren Sie das Labdoo Team contact@labdoo.org, unter Angabe Ihrer E-Mailadresse, der Tagging Nummer der gespendeten Teile und einer kurzen Erklärung. Folgende Vorfälle müssen immer gemeldet werden:
    (2,1) Bei irreparablen Schäden, so dass das Teil problemlos recycelt werden kann.
    (2,2) Wenn eine IT-Spende nicht funktioniert oder bei jeder Änderung seines Status.
(3) Bitte senden Sie alle sechs Monate eine E-Mail mit der Liste der Laptops an contact@labdoo.org, die Sie einsetzen und deren Status (ob sie funktionieren oder nicht funktionieren) .

(4) Sie erhalten die Labdoo laptops kostenlos für Bildungszwecke. Im Gegenzug stimmen Sie zu, dass die Laptops nicht für kommerzielle Zwecke genutzt werden. Sie stimmen mit diesem Antrag zu, keine Gebühr für die Nutzung der Computer verlangt wird.

(5) Mit Abgabe dieses ausgefüllten Antrages bestätigt der Antragsteller gegenüber Labdoo.org, dass er alle Rechte an jetzt oder zukünftig  eingereichten Unterlagen hat und Labdoo.org die Erlaubnis erteilt, diese zu veröffentlichen. Weiterhin bestätigt der Antragssteller, dass er von allen Kindern und/oder Personen, die von Labdoos IT-Sachspende profitieren, deren Erlaubnis zur Aufnahme von Fotos von ihren Eltern und/oder gesetzlichen Vertretern vorliegen hat. Labdoo.org weist ausdrücklich darauf hin, dass eingereichte Unterlagen und Fotos offline und online veröffentlich werden und somit auch Dritten zugänglich sind. Die Fotos verwendet Labdoo.org ausschließlich, um Transparenz und Nachvollziehbarkeit des Projektes zu ermöglichen.

Wir danken Ihnen für Ihr Engagement, um unsere Welt zu verbessern und wir wünschen Ihnen viel Glück bei Ihrem Hilfsprojekt bzw. ihrem humanitären Projekt.

Das Labdoo Team

<strong>Romanian Version</strong>

Fundamentare Proiect Computere Labdoo

Informatii solicitant:
=================
Nume si prenume:
Adresa E-mail:
Nume institutiei :
Website institutie:
Numele contului Labdoo: (va este necesar pentru a permite Labdoo sa va repartizeze computere - va puteti inregistra aici: https://www.labdoo.org/user/register)
Titlul proiectului dvs: 


Date Project:
=============
1.  Rezumat proiect: ( Va rugam faceti o scurta descriere a scopului in care vor fi folosite computerele in cadrul organizatiei dvs)
2.  Locul de desfasurare a proiectului:
3.  Limbile preferate: (2 variante, in ordinea prioritatii)
4.  Informatii de contact (se va indica cel putin o cale de contact):
    4.1. Nume:
    4.2. Telefon:
    4.3. Email:
    4.4. Adresa postala (strada, localitate, cod postal, tara...):
    4.5. Coordonate GPS (daca le cunoasteti sau le puteti afla):
5.  Numar necesar de computere:
6.  Numar de elevi:
7.  Numar de profesori:
8.  Tip alimentare electrica la locul instalarii: (Tensiune si tip priza, de ex tip A, B, C, D, etc. vedeti explicatii la: http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/AC_power_plugs_and_sockets)
9.  Aveti acces la Internet la locul instalarii ? [da / nu]
    9.1. Internetul este disponibil wireless sau prin cablu?
10. Conditii despre locul instalarii computerelor:
    10.1. Este sigur? [da / nu + detalii]
    10.2. Poate fi incuiat pentru a permite supraveghetorilor (profesorilor) sa controleze accesul? [da / nu + detalii]
    10.3. Asigura spatiul protectie impotriva conditiilor climaterice? (de ex,impotriva ploii, umiditatii, prafului, temperaturilor extreme, etc?) [da / nu + detalii]

***Solicitarea computerelor Labdoo implica acordul dvs. cu privire la setul de conditii incluse in "Acordul beneficiarului computerelor Labdoo".

Acordul beneficiarului computerelor Labdoo:
=====================================

Dragi beneficiari ai computerelor Labdoo:

Suntem foarte multumiti ca am avut ocazia sa contribuim la realizarea proiectului dvs, furnizandu-va tehnologia necesara reducerii arieratului informatic in zona dvs de interes.

Orice beneficiu implica insa si o responsabilitate. Tehnologia, atunci cand este folosita corespunzator poate reprezenta un mijloc foarte eficient pentru a-i ajuta pe cei care au intr-adevar nevoie. Daca insa aceasta este folosita intr-un mod impropriu, ii poate afecta pe cei care o folosesc si mediul in care acestia traiesc. Prin primirea computerelor mai sus mentionate se considera ca acceptati respectarea urmatoarelor reguli generale Labdoo:

(1) Articolele primite vor fi utilizate doar in scopul pe care institutia dvs l-a precizat la momentul solicitarii prezentei donatii. Daca intentinati sa le folositi in alte scopuri, veti contacta mai intai echipa Labdoo la adresa contact@labdoo.org.

(2) In cazul in care se produce vreun eveniment cu privire la unul sau mai multe din articolele primite, veti contacta echipa Labdoo la contact@labdoo.org, incluzand in E-mail-ul dvs. numarul de inregistrare Labdoo si o scurta descriere a problemei aparute. Urmatoarele evenimente vor fi intodeauna raportate:
 (2.1) Sfarsitul duratei de viata a sistemului primit, pentru a putea recicla corespunzator produsul.
(2.2) Cand produsul a suferit distrugeri, defectiuni sau orice alterare a starii sale normale de functionare.

(3) La fiecare 6 luni, veti trimite un E-mail pe adresa contact@labdoo.org, atasand lista computerelor si starea lor (functionale sau nefunctionale).

(4) Computerele Labdoo sunt oferite in mod gratuit in scopuri educationale. Veti fi de acord sa nu le folositi  in scopuri comerciale sau sa nu solicitati vreo taxa pentru folosirea acestora.  

Va multumim pentru implicarea in actiunile noastre care vizeaza construirea unei lumi mai bune cu sanse egale pentru toti, prin eliminarea decalajelor informatice si va dorim succes in realizare proiectelor dvs.
Institutie:                                           	Localitate:				Data:
Nume si prenume reprezentant legal :						Semnatura:
Nume si prenume sef proiect:							Semnatura:

<strong>Spanish Version</strong>

Formato de solicitud de laptops de Labdoo.
rev. 001

Información del receptor:
======================
Tu nombre:
Tu dirección de correo electrónico:
Tu organización :
El sitio web de tu organización:
Tu username de Labdoo.org: (esto es necesario para que Labdoo pueda asignar
 laptops a tu proyecto. Puedes registrarte aquí: https://www.labdoo.org/user/register)
Título del proyecto: (un nombre breve para tu proyecto)

Instalaciones del proyecto:
=============
1.  Resumen del proyecto: (Por favor escribe un párrafo sobre la finalidad 
que tendrán las laptops en las instalaciones de tu proyecto.)
2.  Localización del proyecto:
3.  Idiomas de preferencia:
4.  Información de contacto en el sitio (por favor provee por lo menos una manera de contactarte):
    4.1. Nombre:
    4.2. Teléfono:
    4.3. Correo electrónico:
    4.4. Dirección (calle, número, colonia, ciudad, código postal, país):
    4.5. Coordenadas de GPS (si las sabes o puedes averiguarlas):
5.  Número de laptops que se necesitan:
6.  Número de estudiantes:
7.  Número de profesores:
8.  Electricidad en las instalaciones: (Voltaje y tipo de conectores, por ejemplo tipo A, B, C, D, etc.; 
Ver el siguiente enlace para una explicación mas detallada: http://es.wikipedia.org/wiki/Enchufe)
9.  ¿Hay acceso a internet en el sitio? [si / no]
    9.1. ¿El acceso es inalámbrico o por cable?
10. Condiciones sobre el cuarto donde se instalarán las laptops:
    10.1. ¿Es seguro? [sí / no + breve explicación]
    10.2. ¿Puede cerrarse de manera que los supervisores (ejemplo: profesores) puedan controlar el acceso? [sí / no + breve explicación]
    10.3. ¿El cuarto protege del clima? (ejemplo. El cuarto protegería las laptops de lluvia, arena, etc?) [si / no + breve explicación]


*** El solicitar laptops de Labdoo implica que al recibirlas el receptor está de acuerdo 
con el "Acuerdo de recepción de laptops de Labdoo".



Acuerdo de recepción de laptops
====================================

Estimado receptor de laptops,

Estamos muy contentos de tener la oportunidad de contribuir a su proyecto
al proporcionar la tecnología para ayudar a reducir la brecha digital.
Con todo derecho vienen responsabilidades. La tecnología, cuando se
utiliza adecuadamente, puede proporcionar medios muy poderosos para
ayudar a aquellos que más lo necesitan. Pero si se usa incorrectamente,
puede también dañar el medio ambiente. 

Al recibir el equipo que solicitó, automáticamente usted acepta cumplir con 
las siguientes responsabilidades globales de Labdoo:

(1) Los artículos recibidos serán utilizados únicamente para la finalidad
descrita por su organización en el momento en que solicitó la donación. Si
desea utilizarlos para un propósito diferente, tendrá que contactar primero al
equipo de Labdoo a través de contact@labdoo.org.

(2) En el caso de que algún incidente ocurra a cualquiera de los artículos
recibidos, usted se comunicará con el equipo de Labdoo en
contact@labdoo.org, incluyendo en su correo electrónico el número de etiqueta 
de los artículos relacionados con el incidente y una breve
explicación. Las siguientes incidencias siempre deben ser reportadas:

	(2,1) El final de la vida de cualquiera de los artículos recibidos, de
modo que el artículo pueda ser debidamente reciclado.

	(2,2) Cuando un elemento se rompa, presente mal funcionamiento, o haya 
cualquier cambio en su estado.

(3) Cada seis meses, por favor envíe un correo electrónico a
contact@labdoo.org con la lista de los ordenadores portátiles que usted
tiene y su estado (funciona o no funciona).

(4) Las laptops de Labdoo son ofrecidas sin ningún cost a usted, para propósitos educativos. 
A cambio, usted se compromete a no utilizar las laptops para ningún fin comercial no 
cobrar ningún tipo de tarifa por su uso.

Le damos las gracias por su compromiso para hacer de nuestro mundo un
lugar mejor y le deseamos lo mejor de las suertes en su misión
humanitaria.

El equipo de Labdoo.
</value>
</body>
<body>
<type>format</type>
<value>filtered_html_advanced</value>
</body>
<bid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>41</value>
</bid>
<plid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>934</value>
</plid>
<mlid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>936</value>
</mlid>
<weight>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>-13</value>
</weight>
</book>
