<book>
<nid>
<type>node_id</type>
<value>101</value>
</nid>
<title>
<type>node_title</type>
<value>Add a local printer as network printer</value>
</title>
<field_book_language>
<type>value</type>
<value>English</value>
</field_book_language>
<field_is_first_page>
<type>value</type>
<value>1</value>
</field_is_first_page>
<field_reference_book>
<type>target_id</type>
<value>101</value>
</field_reference_book>
<body>
<type>value</type>
<value>If a printer is not installed via LAN in a network, but locally via USB or Centronics cable at a Linux computer you can allow other computers in the network to access to this printer. 

Therefore the CUPS (Common Unix Printing System) must be installed – it is part of  Lubuntu repository.

<strong>Go to the computer, which is linked to the printer:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Open the web browser and type the address http://localhost:631</li>
<li>Allow printer access</li>
<li>On page http://localhost:631/admin/ tick at “Share printers connected to this system”. </li>
<li>Alternatively use this command in a terminal: <code>cupsctl –share-printers</code>    (Enter)</li>
<li>Select on page ”printer” the connected printer. </li>
<li>Click in menu “administration” on “printer”.</li>
<li>Leave “actual connection” unchanged  → Proceed →  add a tick to “allow access to this printer / share”; </li>
<li>optional: Add a name for the place of installation → proceed →  change printer.</li>
</ul>

<strong>Show printer on other computers in the network (has to be done on each computer in the network)</strong>
<ul>
<li>To show the printer on all computers in the network → http://localhost:631/admin → tick “Show printers shared by other systems”  → Change settings → acknowledge, ready.</li>
<li>Alternatively run in a terminal: <code>cupsctl --remote-printers</code>  (Enter)</li>
</ul>

After this you should see the printer in the menu “printer”. Maybe you have to wait a while before the printer is shown or re-load the page.</value>
</body>
<body>
<type>format</type>
<value>filtered_html_advanced</value>
</body>
<bid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>35</value>
</bid>
<plid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>857</value>
</plid>
<mlid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>885</value>
</mlid>
<weight>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>-9</value>
</weight>
</book>
