<book>
<nid>
<type>node_id</type>
<value>19301</value>
</nid>
<title>
<type>node_title</type>
<value>Tagging procedures</value>
</title>
<field_book_language>
<type>value</type>
<value>English</value>
</field_book_language>
<field_is_first_page>
<type>value</type>
<value>1</value>
</field_is_first_page>
<field_reference_book>
<type>target_id</type>
<value>19301</value>
</field_reference_book>
<body>
<type>value</type>
<value>The donated laptop needs to be tagged and labelled with its unique Labdoo ID number for easiness of tracing its parts and location.

The following steps describe the process of tagging a Labdoo laptop.

<ol>
<li>
Login to www.labdoo.org. You need to "Login" (top right of the page) in order to tag a laptop.
</li>
<li>
On the top pull-down menu, select "Dootronics" -> "Tag it!"
</li>
<li>
Fill the laptop information (You have to answer all the fields ended with a "*")
</li>
<li>
It's very important to add the laptop donor's email address to ensure the donor can receive email updates about the status of the laptop.  Here's how:
    - Under Create Dootronic, select the second tab "Additional Information".
    - Scroll down to 'Additional notification emails'.
    - Fill the donor's email address here.
</li>
<li>
Click "Save" once you are done. A unique Labdoo ID number will be assigned to the laptop.
</li>
<li>
On the new page after clicking 'save', click on "Print tags" to print the "Labdoo ID" labels. (Alternatively, you can manually write the Labdoo ID number on the preprint blank label sheets that you will find in this linkL https://www.labdoo.org/sites/default/files/content/labdoo-toolkit/labdoo-laptop_id_labels.pdf).
</li>
<li>
Tape the labels to the laptop, its power adaptor, and all the parts which come with the laptop. Ensure the taping is resistant so that the label does not get detached from the laptop.
</li>
</ol>

Below you will find a picture with an example of the tagging information that needs to be filled in.

<hr/>
<table align="center">
<tr><td>
<em> Figure. Example of tagging procedure.</em>
</td></tr>
<tr><td>
<img src="/sites/default/files/superhubs/labdoo-oc/tagging.png" width="800"/>
</td></tr>
</table>
<hr/>
</value>
</body>
<body>
<type>format</type>
<value>filtered_html_advanced</value>
</body>
<bid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>35</value>
</bid>
<plid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>819</value>
</plid>
<mlid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>1153</value>
</mlid>
<weight>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>-15</value>
</weight>
</book>
