<book>
<nid>
<type>node_id</type>
<value>102</value>
</nid>
<title>
<type>node_title</type>
<value>Special HTML tags</value>
</title>
<field_book_language>
<type>value</type>
<value>English</value>
</field_book_language>
<field_is_first_page>
<type>value</type>
<value>1</value>
</field_is_first_page>
<field_reference_book>
<type>target_id</type>
<value>102</value>
</field_reference_book>
<body>
<type>value</type>
<value>The body section of a wiki page allows writers to use a simplified form of HTML tags to help them format their content. While the page <a href="/filter/tips">'Compose tips'</a> (a link to this page is provided at the bottom of the "body" field in the wiki form) provides a detail description of each of the HTML tags supported by the Labdoo wiki system, in this section we provide additional information for some of the tags that are a bit more advanced. 

<strong>Inserting images</strong>

As explained in the <a href="/filter/tips">'Compose tips'</a>, you can insert an image using the &lt;img&gt; tag. For instance, the following tag:

<code>&lt;img src="/profiles/labdoo/files/pictures/laptop.png" height="50" width="50"&gt;</code>

generates this image:

<img src="/profiles/labdoo/files/pictures/laptop.png" height="50" width="50"/>

To upload the actual image, follow the next steps:

<ul>
<li>
Click on "My account" to go to your account.
</li>
<li>
Click on the "File browser" tab. (If you don't see this tab, it's because you don't have enough permissions. Send an email to contact@labdoo.org to get your permissions upgraded.)
</li>
<li>
You will see a file system directory tree. Next, make sure to select the folder 'content', as this is the folder used to upload images for wiki content. Please notice that if you select a folder outside 'content', your image may not correctly display in future releases of the Labdoo platform. As an option, you can also create a new directory inside 'content' by clicking on the "Directory" tab and select that new folder as the place where you upload your image.
</li>
<li>
Click on "Upload" to complete the uploading of your image.
</li>
<li>
Double click on the image you just uploaded. This will take you to the new image page on a new browser page. You can now copy the URL of this image page from your browser. Use this URL in the "src=" field of your &lt;img&gt; tag.
</li>
</ul>

<strong> Formatting figures in your wiki page </strong>

If you want to insert an image into your text, please follow the following format:

<ul>
<li>
Add a &lt;hr&gt; tag before and after your image to display a separating line.
</li>
<li>
Add a 'Figure' capture inside &lt;em&gt; tags on top of the image.
</li>
<li>
Add both the figure capture and the figure itself inside a table &lt;table&gt; center aligned.
</li>
</ul>

Here is an example:

<code>&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;table align="center"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;em&gt; Figure. This is the Labdoo logo.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;img src="/profiles/labdoo/files/pictures/laptop.png" height="50" width="50"/&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;</code>

Which is displayed as follows:

<hr/>
<table align="center">
<tr><td>
<em> Figure. This is the Labdoo logo.</em>
</td></tr>
<tr><td>
<img src="/profiles/labdoo/files/pictures/laptop.png" height="50" width="50"/>
</td></tr>
</table>
<hr/>

<strong>Inserting videos</strong>

You may insert videos using the following simple tag:

<img src="/sites/default/files/content/wikibook-the-labdoo-social-network-how-it-works/video-filter.png"/>

For a good description on how to insert videos please directly refer to the <a href="/filter/tips">'Compose tips'</a> page under the 'Video Filter' section.</value>
</body>
<body>
<type>format</type>
<value>filtered_html_advanced</value>
</body>
<bid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>77</value>
</bid>
<plid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>833</value>
</plid>
<mlid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>843</value>
</mlid>
<weight>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>-13</value>
</weight>
</book>
