<book>
<nid>
<type>node_id</type>
<value>111</value>
</nid>
<title>
<type>node_title</type>
<value>Edoovillages</value>
</title>
<field_book_language>
<type>value</type>
<value>English</value>
</field_book_language>
<field_is_first_page>
<type>value</type>
<value>1</value>
</field_is_first_page>
<field_reference_book>
<type>target_id</type>
<value>111</value>
</field_reference_book>
<body>
<type>value</type>
<value>Edoovillages are schools where laptops are deployed.  Labdoo focuses on equipping schools because:

<ul>
<li>
Schools have their own organized community.
</li>
<li>
Classrooms are managed by teachers which can help monitor the good use of the laptops.  The role of the teachers is also important to help Labdoo recycle laptops once they no longer work.
</li>
<li>
Schools typically have electricity and access to the Internet (even in remote areas thanks to the expansion of wireless communications). They also provide water-proof and secure shelters.
</li>
<li>
Working with schools simplifies also the coordination of dootrips, as many travellers to poor communities visit schools in their trips.
</li>
</ul>

In order to create a new edoovillage, the potential recipients will need to fill in the “Labdoo laptop request form” XXX.

When an edoovillage is created, the recipients receive a kit containing at least:

<ul>
<li>
An edoovillage dashboard from where the inventory of contributed devices can be managed and tracked. 
</li>
<li>
An entry in the list of Labdoo edoovillages.
</li>
<li>
A web album inside the edoovillage space where pictures of the edoovillages activities can be uploaded.
</li>
</ul>
To help reduce electronic waste, a main obligation of the laptop recipients is to report back to Labdoo.org every six months the list of laptops under their inventory and their status (working or not working) and facilitate the process of recycling the laptops once they no longer work through the Labdoo's social network-based recycling mechanism.  This reporting processes are referred as Global Inventory Checks (GICs) XXX.
</value>
</body>
<body>
<type>format</type>
<value>filtered_html_advanced</value>
</body>
<bid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>80</value>
</bid>
<plid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>846</value>
</plid>
<mlid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>852</value>
</mlid>
<weight>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>0</value>
</weight>
</book>
