<book>
<nid>
<type>node_id</type>
<value>173</value>
</nid>
<title>
<type>node_title</type>
<value>Offline WIKIs and OER (Open Educational Resources)</value>
</title>
<field_book_language>
<type>value</type>
<value>English</value>
</field_book_language>
<field_is_first_page>
<type>value</type>
<value>1</value>
</field_is_first_page>
<field_reference_book>
<type>target_id</type>
<value>173</value>
</field_reference_book>
<body>
<type>value</type>
<value><font color="red">
[Please print and attach this sheet to your dootronic shipment to ensure that the recipient knows how to use the computer. To print this sheet, click on 'Printer-friendly version' at the bottom of this page. Make sure to print it using the double page option in your printer settings to minimize the amount of paper used. Also, please print only one copy of this document for each group of laptops shipped together.]
</font>

All below mentioned documents can be downloaded from http://ftp.labdoo.org/download/Public/. If a Labdoo laptop was installed using Labdoo images for cloning the English content is pre-installed.

For an easy download we recommend rsync http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rsync. Rsync is available for a lot of operating systems, e.g. Windows, Apple or Ubuntu: http://wiki.ubuntuusers.de/rsync

Or even easier, use our installation script for content http://ftp.labdoo.org/download/images/installskripts/installscript-content.sh.

If you added own content to the folder /home/labdoo/Public and if you want to make sure that all users of the group labdoo (user student as well) gets access please use this script: http://ftp.labdoo.org/download/images/installskripts/set-rights-folder-files-Public-correct.sh.

<ol>

<li><strong>Wikipedia for schools (wikidoo, recommended)</strong></li>

<table> <tr><th> </th></tr>

<tr>
<td>For schools speaking English Labdoo.org recommends "Wikipedia for schools', following the UK National Curriculum : http://www.sos-schools.org/wikipedia-for-schools or http://ftp.labdoo.org/download/Public/wikidoo/, called wikidoo. </td>

<td><img src="/sites/default/files/content/wiki-de/edoovillages/wikidoo01.png" width="300"/>  </td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td>Wikidoo will be used, if schools have none or a very slow internet access. This themes were selected and filtered for children. Labdoo calls the wiki "wikidoo". 

Wikidoo comes with about 6,000 themes, 26 mio. words and 50,000 pictures (released 10/2013). To start click on file:///home/labdoo/Public/wikidoo/index.htm
</td>

<td><img src="/sites/default/files/content/wiki-de/edoovillages/wikidoo02.png" width="300"/>  </td>
</tr> 

</table>

<li><strong>RACHEL Offline content (English or Spanish, optional)</strong></li>

<table> <tr><th> </th></tr>

<tr>
<td>RACHEL, a collection of license-free content, is recommended for use in English or Spanish speaking coutries http://www.worldpossible.org/rachel/. „Wikipedia for schools“ (wikidoo, see above) is part of the RACHEL collection, but also educational documents of the Khan Academy (math and science classes), MedLine Medical Encyclopedia, Hesperian Health Guides, Khan Academy (health videos), CK-12 STEM text-books, Gutenberg World Literature eBooks, OLPC Educational Games/ Lessons, UNESCO Primary School Resources, MathExpression Math Videos, Learn to Type "Power Typing", Music Theory, MIT Scratch etc..
</td>

<td><img src="/sites/default/files/content/wiki-de/edoovillages/rachel.jpg" width="300"/>  </td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td>
ACHEL can be installed locally and read in a browser (recommended). The download comes also with reader and server software for tablets (Android), server and for Windows, but those are not needed. 

The English content takes 22,5 GB on a disc-drive. When you remove the wikidoo folder (6,5 GB) you need in total additional 16 GB more vompared to a wikidoo installation. The English RACHEL collection can be downloaded from here (please select the file with the highest release number) http://rachelfriends.org/rachelusb_32EN/

The Spanish RACHEL version can be found here http://rachelfriends.org/rachelusb_32ES/

Download the ZIP files and unzip them into a new folder /home/labdoo/Public/RACHEL. The next steps are described here https://www.labdoo.org/content/install-rachel.</td>

<td><img src="/sites/default/files/content/wiki-de/edoovillages/rachel02_small.png" width="300"/>  </td>
</tr> 

</table>


<li><strong>Xowa – Wikis</strong></li>

<table> <tr><th> </th></tr>

<tr>
<td>If wikis (lexicon) are needed in other languages than English Labdoo.org recommends Xowa, a tool to import and export more than 800 offline wikis in various languages: http://xowa.sourceforge.net/image_dbs.html. There are more than 800 Xowa-Wikis. </td>

<td><img src="/sites/default/files/content/wiki-de/edoovillages/xowa.png" width="100"/>  </td>
</tr>

</table>

<li><strong>Multimedia English course http://www.englishbanana.com/</strong></li>

<table> <tr><th> </th></tr>

<tr>
<td>A free offline English course is also kept in the folder /Public: file:///home/labdoo/Public/eBooks/English%20Language%20Training%20Version%203.0/index.html. Download from here http://ftp.labdoo.org/download/Public/eBooks/English%20Language%20Training%20Version%203.0/</td>

<td><img src="/sites/default/files/content/wiki-de/edoovillages/english01.png" width="300"/>  </td>
</tr>

</table>

<li><strong>OER – Open Educational Resources</strong></li>

Labdoo helper collect OER – Open Educational Resources, copy-left, free educational content in various languages. Who wants to contribute is welcome. You can send-in OER or as native speaker search for content in “your” language.

The collected OER can be found here (/English should be pre-installed) http://ftp.labdoo.org/download/Public/eBooks/eBooks%20Collection/ (the content of the folder /english is pre-installed, if using images or installation script for content)

<li><strong>Lubuntu / LXDE manuals, Labdoo Wikis</strong></li>

In the folder /home/labdoo/Public/wikis you will find these wikis, which will be updated every 3 months (beginning of a quarter):

- help.ubuntu.com
- wiki.lxde.org
- wiki.labdoo.org

Maybe you are right now reading our wiki offline on your laptop? ;)

<li><strong>Free VIP access to http://www.Free-eBooks.net</strong></li>

Labdoo Edoovillages get a free VIP access to the website 
http://www.Free-eBooks.net. This portal offers one of the largest pool of free e-Books in English, Spanish or Portuguese language.

Please create a free basic user (login) at www.Free-eBooks.net. Using this free basic account you have only limited access, being able to download a few e-books per week.

To get an unlimited VIP access please send an English e-mail to Nic nic@free-ebooks.net, tell him your login (user) and ask him to change the account into a VIP account. Please refer to the agreement between Free-eBooks.net and Labdoo.org. We are grateful for the  support and the great offer of Free-eBooks.net.

</ol></value>
</body>
<body>
<type>format</type>
<value>filtered_html_advanced</value>
</body>
<bid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>142</value>
</bid>
<plid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>926</value>
</plid>
<mlid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>957</value>
</mlid>
<weight>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>-14</value>
</weight>
</book>
