<book>
<nid>
<type>node_id</type>
<value>27022</value>
</nid>
<title>
<type>node_title</type>
<value>Take Pictures and Upload them to the Photo Album</value>
</title>
<field_book_language>
<type>value</type>
<value>English</value>
</field_book_language>
<field_is_first_page>
<type>value</type>
<value>1</value>
</field_is_first_page>
<field_reference_book>
<type>target_id</type>
<value>27022</value>
</field_reference_book>
<body>
<type>value</type>
<value>Remember to take a good amount of pictures of your trip. Pictures are important to keep the Labdoo platform transparent and open. They are the best way to demonstrate that the donated laptops reach their intended destination. Please make sure that the pictures:

(1) are of good quality.
(2) clearly illustrate the laptops and allow donors to recognize their contributed laptop. 
(3) clearly portray the students using the laptops in their classroom.

Here is an example of an album of pictures for <a href="../content/kenya-nairobi-shiroz-library-resource-centre-photo-album">one recipient school</a>. The edoovillage where you are bringing the laptops also has it's own page and photo album. If you don't know the URL, make sure to ask the manager of your edoovillage project or contact Labdoo at contact@labdoo.org.

Make sure you upload the pictures to the photo album of the edoovillage you are visiting. If you don't have enough rights to upload pictures to that album, ask your edoovillage manager to grant you the necessary rights or send him/her the pictures so he/she can upload them for you. You will find all this information in that edoovillage page.

<hr/>
<table align="center">
<tr><td>
<em> Figure. Good pictures allow donors to recognize (1) their laptop and (2) the students using their laptop at a school.</em>
</td></tr>
<tr><td>
<img src="/sites/default/files/content/dootripper-wiki/pangna-villay-cambodia.jpg" width="800"/>
</td></tr>
</table>
<hr/>


</value>
</body>
<body>
<type>format</type>
<value>filtered_html_advanced</value>
</body>
<bid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>141</value>
</bid>
<plid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>925</value>
</plid>
<mlid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>1492</value>
</mlid>
<weight>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>-12</value>
</weight>
</book>
