<book>
<nid>
<type>node_id</type>
<value>37</value>
</nid>
<title>
<type>node_title</type>
<value>Installing Additional Education Packages Using Scripts</value>
</title>
<field_book_language>
<type>value</type>
<value>English</value>
</field_book_language>
<field_is_first_page>
<type>value</type>
<value>1</value>
</field_is_first_page>
<field_reference_book>
<type>target_id</type>
<value>37</value>
</field_reference_book>
<body>
<type>value</type>
<value>In addition to installing the base Edubuntu education package, users are encouraged to also install a set of additional powerful education resources. These additional resources are installed by executing a set of scripts through a simple process described in this section. If you have questions or suggestions please write your messages directly in the <a href="../content/quality-assurance-qa/activities">Labdoo QA Team Wall</a>.

<strong>List of Available Scripts</strong>

All Labdoo scripts can be downloaded from the FTP server http://ftp.labdoo.org/download/images/installskripts/
To execute a script the computer must be connected to the Internet.

Recommended scripts:
<ul>
<li>
installscript-content.sh
http://ftp.labdoo.org/download/images/installskripts/installscript-content.sh
This script installs educational content including offline wikis (Xowa), license-free educational content, English eBooks, and multimedia language courses for English. Usage of an external USB-disk or USB-stick requires storage of 16 GB.
</li>
<li>
installscript-software.sh
http://ftp.labdoo.org/download/images/installskripts/installscript-software.sh
This script installs additional software, including barrier free access for handicapped users, tools, and virus scanner among others.
</li>
</ul>

Additional helpful scripts (optional):

<ul>
<li>
installscript-codecs.sh
http://ftp.labdoo.org/download/images/installskripts/installscript-codecs.sh
This script installs codecs and multimedia software for audio and video. Please ensure the legal situation in your country to install these packages.
</li>
<li>
set-rights-folder-files-Public-correct.sh
http://ftp.labdoo.org/download/images/installskripts/set-rights-folder-files-Public-correct.sh
This script sets the rights to folder /home/labdoo/Public, so that the student users will have access to the content in this folder as well
</li>
<li>
check_cpu_32_or_64_bits_PAE_or_nonPAE.sh
http://ftp.labdoo.org/download/images/installskripts/check_cpu_32_or_64_bits_PAE_or_nonPAE.sh
This script will tell you which type of CPU is installed in your computer (it does not include any educational software.)
</li>
</ul>

Scripts for special usages (usually only for experienced users):

<ul>
<li>
installscript-xowa.sh
http://ftp.labdoo.org/download/images/installskripts/installscript-xowa.sh
This script installs the offline wiki tool Xowa and sets proper folder rights
</li>
<li>
installscript-desktops.sh
http://ftp.labdoo.org/download/images/installskripts/installscript-desktops.sh
This script installs additional desktops (user interface, GUI) as Unity and Gnome. They require more hardware resources such as bigger memory
</li>
<li>
installscript-virtualbox.sh
http://ftp.labdoo.org/download/images/installskripts/installscript-virtualbox.sh
This script installs VirtualBox, a tool to run Windows or other guest operating systems on top of the host Linux system. Requires a minimum of 2 GB RAM and Dual Core CPU is recommended plus a legal license.
</li>
<li>
'childsplay bug fix.txt'
http://ftp.labdoo.org/download/images/installskripts/childsplay%20bug%20fix.txt
This file is only needed if the application Childsplay does not start and provides an explanation on how to fix this bug (only needed if you are running Lubuntu 12.04 LTS, fixed in 14.04 LTS
</li>
<li>
delete-xowa-log-folder.txt
http://ftp.labdoo.org/download/images/installskripts/delete-xowa-log-folder.txt
Use this execute in a terminal if you want to produce images for cloning by yourself and Xowa is part of the image)
</li>
</ul>

The following steps describe how to install a script.

<strong>Step 1. Download a Script</strong> 
- Right click with your mouse on one of the script links that you will find in the download folder (http://ftp.labdoo.org/download/images/installskripts/)
- Select "Save link as" and save the file in the desktop of a Labdoo laptop (/home/labdoo/Desktop).

<strong>Step 2. Execute a Script</strong> 
Open a terminal (press CTL and Alt and T at the same time) and execute the following commands:

<code>cd ~/Desktop</code>
<code>ls</code>
<code>chmod u+x ./installscript-content.sh</code>
<code>sudo ./installscript-content.sh</code>

(change the script 'installscript-content.sh' for the name of the script you want to install.)

<strong>Hint. </strong>Some scripts will ask for passwords or settings through the installation process. Please keep an eye on the screen to provide the necessary inputs.

<strong>Hint. </strong>Some scripts are fast, some need hours. It depends on the speed of your internal connection and on the speed of the laptop. 

[video:https://youtu.be/aaSgbkCmiJU]
</value>
</body>
<body>
<type>format</type>
<value>filtered_html_advanced</value>
</body>
<bid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>35</value>
</bid>
<plid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>846</value>
</plid>
<mlid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>821</value>
</mlid>
<weight>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>-13</value>
</weight>
</book>
