<book>
<nid>
<type>node_id</type>
<value>50</value>
</nid>
<title>
<type>node_title</type>
<value>To make a script executable</value>
</title>
<field_book_language>
<type>value</type>
<value>English</value>
</field_book_language>
<field_is_first_page>
<type>value</type>
<value>1</value>
</field_is_first_page>
<field_reference_book>
<type>target_id</type>
<value>50</value>
</field_reference_book>
<body>
<type>value</type>
<value><strong>To make a script executable</strong> -&gt; right mouse click on the script icon once stored on desktop -&gt; properties  -&gt; Permissions (2nd tab) -&gt; Execute: Only owner and group -&gt; ok

Most scripts need to be executed as administrator (super-user). Some scripts must even be executed as super-user. So follow these steps:

<strong>Execute a script as administrator (super-user)</strong> -&gt; <a href="https://dev.labdoo.org/content/terminalfenster-%C3%B6ffnen">open a terminal</a> -&gt; <code>cd Desktop</code> (enter) to navigate to the Desktop -&gt; <code>sudo ./installscript...sh</code> (the name of the script incl. .sh at the end) (Enter) -&gt; if password is asekd enter password, script will start.

<strong>1st hint:</strong> after enter <code>cd Desktop</code> type <code>ls</code> in terminal -&gt; will list all files in the folder Desktop -&gt; mark the script name using the mouse -&gt; either press at the same time Shift + CTL + c or right mouse click "copy" -&gt; type <code>sudo ./</code> -&gt; either press at the same time Shift + CTL + v or reight mouse click + paste -&gt; so you do not have to type the name of the script :)

<strong>2nd hint</strong> When executing the script <code>installscript-content.sh</code> please connect and open with file manager an external USB-drive/stick. It must be "mounted", so open it in the beginning with the file manager PacManFM and check, if in the top directory a folder <strong>Public</strong> is created (if not, please do so). When executing this script the first time about 9 GB of data will be downloaded from our FTP server. In a second step these files will be copied to the Labdoo laptop. Using it once will not save time. But from 2nd usage and more it will be much much faster and will minimize data transfer from our FTP server.

<strong>your input needed: </strong> Some scripts will ask for passwords or settings. Please keep an eye what is proceeded on screen :)

<strong>run time: </strong> Some scripts are fast, some need hours. It depends on the speed of your intern connection and spped of the laptop. Especially the scripts for software and content may take first time 2 to 4 hours (2nd time 20 - 40 minutes using an USB-drive). This gives you an idea who much the children would miss, if you do not run these scripts!

<strong>To end a script: </strong> as soon as you can see the cursor again behind the entry labdoo@000004xxxx:~$ the script has come to an end. Then you can close the terminal window or start a new task or script.

<strong>Recall the last entries:</strong> Use the key ↑ (arrow up) to recall the last entries, it will save you time :)

<strong>Execute a script several times: </strong> All scripts can be executed as often as you want. It is even helpful, as the scripts will check, if the were updates and in case install them. They scripts will need less time, only a few minutes, to check and update. 

But some steps are left, which scripts are not able to solve them automatically. Read more about that in the next chapter.</value>
</body>
<body>
<type>format</type>
<value>filtered_html_advanced</value>
</body>
<bid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>35</value>
</bid>
<plid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>821</value>
</plid>
<mlid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>834</value>
</mlid>
<weight>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>0</value>
</weight>
</book>
