<book>
<nid>
<type>node_id</type>
<value>165</value>
</nid>
<title>
<type>node_title</type>
<value>Labdoo's Zero Funding Approach</value>
</title>
<field_book_language>
<type>value</type>
<value>English</value>
</field_book_language>
<field_is_first_page>
<type>value</type>
<value>1</value>
</field_is_first_page>
<field_reference_book>
<type>target_id</type>
<value>165</value>
</field_reference_book>
<body>
<type>value</type>
<value>You may have noticed that within the Labdoo.org system there is no place for people to make a monetary donation and the platform is 100% advertisement free. That's because Labdoo runs simply out of people's goodwill through the contribution of people's time (global collaboration) and unused resources such as laptops or travelers' luggage space (excess capacity), and therefore we require no investors or any source of funding to carry out our cause. The founders decided to take this approach because of several important reasons:

<ul>
<li>
To run Labdoo, there is no need for money.  The world has so much excess capacity (laptops, travelers, connectivity, goodwill, etc), that we have the capability to solve the digital divide problem without incurring any additional cost (economic or environmental).
</li>
<li>
By removing the money factor, the project's mission becomes clean and focused.  This approach implies that there is no possible confusion on what the objective of the project is and it strengthens its values. The only possible motivation supporting the project is one of making a contribution to the global community.
</li>
<li>
This approach makes Project Labdoo resilient against global economic crisis. A paradox about our economic system is that when there is an economic crisis, social projects are the ones who get the biggest hits in terms of budget cuts. Hence, those that need the biggest help are the ones who get hit first and harder. This is so because of the money-dependency factor in practically all social projects. By removing the money from the equation, Labdoo can continue to operate normally even in the presence of economic recessions. In fact, Project Labdoo was created in the midst of one of the biggest economic recessions of the last 100 years. 
</li>
<li>
The opportunity cost. If we invest $1000 in bringing one laptop to a needy school, automatically we are des-investing $1000 from all other humanitarian projects such as the provision of health care, clean water, shelter, etc. Let's use the money for those projects that really need it.
</li>
<li>
It substantially simplifies the paperwork and the logistics of international cooperation.
</li>
<li>
It allows for exploring new and more sustainable ways to organize global communities toward solving global problems.  
</li>
<li>
The 'how' can be more important than the 'what'. There is a famous sentence that was told once by a famous President: 'We choose to go to the moon, not because it is easy, but because it is hard." This idea reflects a very important concept in human society: the destination you choose to target is important (the 'what' you propose to do), but the path you choose to get there (the 'how' you propose to get there) can be even more important. The reason is that it is the path to that destination that makes you stronger, as a person, as a team, as a society. By choosing to go to the moon, it is not so much what you achieve in reaching a planet that has barely any resources, but it is more about what you learn along the way as a team by attempting to go there together. Through that journey, many new technologies were invented that today we enjoy, and society became more united and encouraged to take positive action than ever before. A new generation of kids became fascinated with what we achieved together and they too decided to become astronauts, scientists, mathematicians, doctors... simply, good men and women. At Labdoo we take the challenge of bringing education to every child in the Planet as an opportunity to make each of us stronger and more united. By choosing the path of open global collaboration, we empower everyone to take action, to learn the skills and to discover the global citizenship character that it takes for all of us to succeed together as one. This intangible, the 'how' you do things, the path you choose to achieve your target, can often (if not always) be more important than the destination you are aiming at itself.
</li>
</ul>
</value>
</body>
<body>
<type>format</type>
<value>filtered_html_advanced</value>
</body>
<bid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>76</value>
</bid>
<plid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>860</value>
</plid>
<mlid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>949</value>
</mlid>
<weight>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>-13</value>
</weight>
</book>
