<book>
<nid>
<type>node_id</type>
<value>27021</value>
</nid>
<title>
<type>node_title</type>
<value>Transport, Customs, and Dootripper Letter</value>
</title>
<field_book_language>
<type>value</type>
<value>English</value>
</field_book_language>
<field_is_first_page>
<type>value</type>
<value>1</value>
</field_is_first_page>
<field_reference_book>
<type>target_id</type>
<value>27021</value>
</field_reference_book>
<body>
<type>value</type>
<value>Before you travel, you need to know:

<ul>
<li>
<strong>Number of laptops you can carry.</strong> Practically all countries accept people carrying 2 laptops without questioning. If you are carrying more than 2 laptops, we recommend that you check the customs rules for the specific country you are traveling to. If you plan to carry more laptops than what the rules allow you to, distribute them equally to the people who are traveling with you. For instance, if you are carrying 6 laptops and you are traveling with 2 more people, have each person carry 2 laptops.
</li>

<li>
<strong>Check in the laptops.</strong> It is recommended that you pack the laptops in a luggage that you will be checking in. This way your laptop will travel all the way to the destination without you having to worry.
</li>

<li>
<strong>For a larger number of laptops, bring a dootripper letter.</strong> If you need to carry more laptops than what the custom rules allow, you will need to explain that the laptops are not for commercial use and that they are for education and humanitarian purposes.  To do so, it is recommended that you print the 'Dootripper letter' which you will find in the <a href="../content/dootrippers-travel-letter">Labdoo Toolkit</a>
If you need to carry more laptops than the custom rules allow, you will need to explain that the laptops are not for commercial use and that they are for education and humanitarian purposes. To do so, it is recommended that you print the 'Dootripper letter' which you will find in the  <a href="../content/dootrippers-travel-letter">Labdoo Toolkit</a>.
</li>

<li>
<strong>Batteries.</strong> Almost all laptop batteries have less than 100 Wh and can be transported without any restriction as a checked in luggage or in your hand luggage. If your battery wattage is less than 100 Wh, an approval of the airline is not required. Otherwise, please check the IATA rules at the time of your traveling or feel free to pose a question to the Labdoo teams community: https://www.labdoo.org/teams. For the latest information, please visit directly: http://www.iata.org/lithiumbatteries.
</li>

<hr/>
<table align="center">
<tr><td>
<em> Figure 1. Lithium batteries you can bring (source: http://www.iata.org/lithiumbatteries).</em>
</td></tr>
<tr><td>
<img src="../sites/default/files/content/labdoo-toolkit/iata-batteries-regulation.png" width="500"/>
</td></tr>
</table>

<hr/>

<table align="center">
<tr><td>
<em> Figure 2. Examples of lithium batteries.</em>
</td></tr>
<tr><td>
<img src="../sites/default/files/content/labdoo-toolkit/iata-batteries-examples.png" width="500"/>
</td></tr>
</table>
<hr/>

</ul></value>
</body>
<body>
<type>format</type>
<value>filtered_html_advanced</value>
</body>
<bid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>141</value>
</bid>
<plid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>925</value>
</plid>
<mlid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>1491</value>
</mlid>
<weight>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>-13</value>
</weight>
</book>
