<book>
<nid>
<type>node_id</type>
<value>145</value>
</nid>
<title>
<type>node_title</type>
<value>Installation of restricted Codecs (please mind the local laws in your country!)</value>
</title>
<field_book_language>
<type>value</type>
<value>English</value>
</field_book_language>
<field_is_first_page>
<type>value</type>
<value>1</value>
</field_is_first_page>
<field_reference_book>
<type>target_id</type>
<value>145</value>
</field_reference_book>
<body>
<type>value</type>
<value><strong>Important: before executing and installing this software please check the legal situation in your country!</strong>

Depending on the local law it might be illegal to install certain codecs, multimedia extensions etc. Here you can find an explanation how to install those extensions, but please check before the local law before installing. Otherwise this might be done later. The focus of Labdoo is education and IT knowledge, but for the children it is also important to view films or multimedia. If this it not possible they might be disappointed.

First install via Lubuntu Software Center → ubuntu-restricted-codecs , select and install. The most important, but not all codecs will be installed.

At the beginning of the installtion you might be asked that 2 program parts will be exchanged. 
→ acknowledge Install Anyway. During the installation you also have to accept an EULA license agreement.

To view (more or less all) DVDs you must also install libdvdcss2 and non-free-codecs (in Medibuntu Repository). But in Europe these repositories are not allowed to use legally. Further information can be read here: http://medibuntu.org/, http://wiki.ubuntuusers.de/Codecs.

Problem using codecs (DVD can not been viewed)

Often codecs are missing to watch DVDs (installation and usage not allowed in some countries!):

Open a terminal and execute:

#------check legal situation before activating these lines / Codecs 

<code>sudo apt-get install ubuntu-restricted-extras -y</code> (Enter)
<code>sudo apt-get install non-free-codecs -y</code> (Enter)

<code>sudo apt-get install curl -y</code> (Enter)
<code>curl ftp://ftp.videolan.org/pub/debian/videolan-apt.asc | </code> (Enter)
<code>sudo apt-key add -echo "deb ftp://ftp.videolan.org/pub/debian/stable ./" | </code> (Enter)
<code>sudo tee /etc/apt/sources.list.d/libdvdcss.list </code> (Enter)
<code>sudo apt-get update</code> (Enter)</value>
</body>
<body>
<type>format</type>
<value>filtered_html_advanced</value>
</body>
<bid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>35</value>
</bid>
<plid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>857</value>
</plid>
<mlid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>929</value>
</mlid>
<weight>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>0</value>
</weight>
</book>
