<book>
<nid>
<type>node_id</type>
<value>92</value>
</nid>
<title>
<type>node_title</type>
<value>WiFi cards will not be detected</value>
</title>
<field_book_language>
<type>value</type>
<value>English</value>
</field_book_language>
<field_is_first_page>
<type>value</type>
<value>1</value>
</field_is_first_page>
<field_reference_book>
<type>target_id</type>
<value>92</value>
</field_reference_book>
<body>
<type>value</type>
<value><strong>1. Initial Considerations.</strong>

Before you check for the cause of a non-functioning wireless card (WiFi) please check that:
<ul>
<li> The wireless LAN (WiFi) function is properly activated via the hardware switch/slider (often on one side of the laptop) or via a function key on the computer keyboard, </li>
<li> There is a wireless card (WiFi) installed (often we get laptop donations without a wireless card), see below <strong>Check which WiFi chip is installed and check the manufacturer name</strong>. In case there is no WiFi card installed you can add one or use a connection via LAN (cable). </li>
</ul>

Sometimes older or very new WiFi Cards are not recognized automatically. The following check list provides a set of steps that you can try to fix this situation.

<strong>2. Check list.</strong>

<ul>
<li><strong>Check if specific drivers are needed</strong></li>
Preferences → Software &amp; Updates → Additional Drivers → wait a while
→ either  "no additional drivers available" is hown → no further action should be needed, or
→ a list of availble drivers is shown → click the driver you want to use → Apply Changes

<li><strong>Check which WiFi chip is installed and check the manufacturer name</strong></li>

Open a terminal and execute:
<code>lspci | grep -i net</code>  	(enter)
or
to show chip set and manufacturer: 
<code>lspci -nnk | grep -i net -A2 </code>	(enter)
or in case of using an USB Wifi stick:
<code>lsusb</code>	(enter)
Note: Some build-in WiFi cards are recognized as an external USB, so if in doubt try also these commands. 

To check if your WiFi card is supported:
https://help.ubuntu.com/community/WifiDocs/WirelessCardsSupported
http://linux-wless.passys.nl/
http://wireless.kernel.org/en/users/Devices
http://wiki.ubuntuusers.de/WLAN/Karten
http://wiki.ubuntuusers.de/Systeminformationen_ermitteln?redirect=no#Hardware

<li><strong>Check if the Broadcom WiFi chip is not detected</strong></li>
If your WiFi card is based on the Broadcom chip set you are able to install:
<code>sudo apt-get update</code>	(enter)
<code>sudo apt-get install firmware-b43-installer</code>	(enter)

After rebooting the system it should work. If not activate the driver by hand:
<code>sudo modprobe -r b43 bcma</code>     (enter)

<li><strong>Try installing Linux Backport Modules</strong></li>

Linux Backport Modules can be installed to get support for many older Wifi cards. The Backport Modules are already part of Labdoo Image for Cloning and installscript-software.sh.

A detailed list of the supported WiFi cards can be found here:
http://wiki.ubuntuusers.de/WLAN/Linux-backports-modules
http://wireless.kernel.org/en/users/Drivers

To install execute in a terminal:
for Lubuntu 12.04: <code>sudo apt-get install linux-backports-modules-cw-3.6-$(uname -r)</code>   (Enter)
for Lubuntu 10.04: <code>sudo apt-get install linux-backports-modules-wireless-$(uname -r)</code>   (Enter)
and for all Lubuntu versions: <code>sudo apt-get install linux-firmware-nonfree</code>	(Enter)

If it does not work you can try:

<li><strong>Try installing NdisWrapper</strong></li>
Details at: http://wiki.ubuntuusers.de/WLAN/NdisWrapper

Please check, if
<ul>
<li>the 32 Bit or 64 Bit driver of the WiFi card matches with your Lubuntu version (32 or 64 Bit)</li>
<li>the .inf file of the driver is enclosed, e.g. Intel encloses .inf only in the .zip version, not enclosed in the .exe!</li>
</ul>
Follow the instruction in the upper Wiki (please add here an English Wiki link). 

If this does not work try:

<li><strong>Try installing the native WiFi driver of the manufacturer.</strong></li> Please search in web for more information.
</ul></value>
</body>
<body>
<type>format</type>
<value>filtered_html_advanced</value>
</body>
<bid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>35</value>
</bid>
<plid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>857</value>
</plid>
<mlid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>876</value>
</mlid>
<weight>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>7</value>
</weight>
</book>
