<book>
<nid>
<type>node_id</type>
<value>20652</value>
</nid>
<title>
<type>node_title</type>
<value>Installing RACHEL Education Package</value>
</title>
<field_book_language>
<type>value</type>
<value>English</value>
</field_book_language>
<field_is_first_page>
<type>value</type>
<value>1</value>
</field_is_first_page>
<field_reference_book>
<type>target_id</type>
<value>20652</value>
</field_reference_book>
<body>
<type>value</type>
<value>RACHEL is a free collection of educational content in English and Spanish. It includes powerful packages such as Wikipedia, Khan Academy, Edison for Robotics, CK-12 Textbooks, UNESCO's IICBA Electronic Library, MedlinePlus Medical Encyclopedia, Great Books of the World, OLPC Educational Packages, or MIT Scratch, among many others. To get an overview of what the package includes, please refer to the project's main page at http://rachelfriends.org/.  A live demo of the package can also be accessed from http://www.rachel.worldpossible.org/.

Rachel occupies about 20-25GB of disk space and it is recommended to install only on disk drives of 50GB or higher.

If you sanitized your laptop using the advanced method and choosing an image that comes with RACHEL preloaded, there is nothing else you will need to do as you will be able to enjoy RACHEL directly out of the box. Otherwise, if you sanitized your laptop using the simple method, then continue reading to manually do the installation.

To install RACHEL, first you need to download the package into your local disk. You can choose to download it from either the RACHEL server http://rachelfriends.org/ or from the Labdoo FTP server http://ftp.labdoo.org/download/RACHEL/. 

<strong>Downloading RACHEL in English</strong>

Download the latest version from RACHEL's server: http://rachelfriends.org/downloads/public_ftp/rachelusb_32EN/
or
from Labdoo's FTP server: http://ftp.labdoo.org/download/RACHEL/RACHEL_EN.tar.gz

<strong>Downloading RACHEL in Spanish</strong>
Download the latest version from RACHEL'sserver: http://rachelfriends.org/downloads/public_ftp/rachelusb_32ES/
or
from Labdoo's FTP server: http://ftp.labdoo.org/download/RACHEL/RACHEL_ES.tar.gz

<strong>Installing RACHEL on a Laptop</strong>
Once you have downloaded RACHEL, unzip it in a new folder <code>/home/labdoo/Public/RACHEL</code> (the downloading and unzipping operations could take a few hours depending on the speed of your network and computer). Once unzipped, double click on the file <code>/home/labdoo/Public/RACHEL/bin/www/starthere.html</code> to open a web browser that will take you to the start page of RACHEL. 

<strong>Note.</strong> The first folder "Wikipedia for Schools" is equivalent to the Xowa package; hence, if your Labdoo laptop already has Xowa installed, you can remove this folder from RACHEL, which will give you back 6,5 GB of disk space.

To make access for users easier, we recommend to make the default web browser page point to RACHEL's initial page. For that, open the web browser (this instructions are for Firefox but similar steps apply to other browsers) and go to <code>File  => Open File  [ navigate to /home/labdoo/Public/RACHEL/bin/www/starthere.html ] => Open</code>. Then go to <code>Edit => Preferences [ opens a window for the settings, click on "Use current Pages" and close the tab "Preferences" ] </code>. Please repeat any of the configuration steps for both the 'labdoo' and the 'student' users.

<strong>Installing RACHEL on a Tablet</strong>

The RACHEL package includes also an installation file for Android (apk file): http://rachelfriends.org/downloads/public_ftp/z-rachelandroid_APK/. But notice that as long as you read the RACHEL content in a web browser on a tablet, it is not necessary to install this apk-file. That means that you can just copy and unzip the RACHEL file to the tablet and open the file starthere.html from the tablet's web browser. With this method, you can therefore use RACHEL with any tablet (not just Android) just by using the tablet's web browser. Some tablets may not have enough built-in disk space to store RACHEL. If that's the case, you will need to include an external storage card and install RACHEL in it. 

<strong>Note.</strong> RACHEL is much more than just content for a web browser as it also includes executable files. Some of these executable files may not be compatible with the Labdoo operating system. However, these additional programs do not take much disk space, and hence we recommend to leave them where they are so that schools abroad can still have the option to copy these tools to other compatible platforms and use them.</value>
</body>
<body>
<type>format</type>
<value>filtered_html_advanced</value>
</body>
<bid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>35</value>
</bid>
<plid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>1280</value>
</plid>
<mlid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>1222</value>
</mlid>
<weight>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>-15</value>
</weight>
</book>
