<book>
<nid>
<type>node_id</type>
<value>20652</value>
</nid>
<title>
<type>node_title</type>
<value>Install RACHEL</value>
</title>
<field_book_language>
<type>value</type>
<value>English</value>
</field_book_language>
<field_is_first_page>
<type>value</type>
<value>1</value>
</field_is_first_page>
<field_reference_book>
<type>target_id</type>
<value>20652</value>
</field_reference_book>
<body>
<type>value</type>
<value>RACHEL is a free collection of educational content in English and Spanish. To get an overview we recommend https://www.Labdoo.org/de/content/offline-wikis-und-oer-open-educational-ressources and http://www.worldpossible.org/rachel/. RACHEL comes with English or Spanish content. Due to the size of 20-25 GB it is recommended to install it on disc-drives of minimum 60 GB or up.

First you must download the needed RACHEL content to your local disc. As this will need up to 22,5 GB depending on the language you will need much time and patience... You can choose, if to download from the RACHEL server http://rachelfriends.org/ or from our Labdoo FTP-Server http://ftp.labdoo.org/download/RACHEL/. There are also releases available for a Pi mini computer and specific tools for LAN/server or Windows. These platforms are (today) of none importance for the Labdoo project so we concentrate in this guideline on the pure content and its usage in a web browser.

<strong> RACHEL in English (actual version 3.1.5, ca. 20 GB)</strong>
Download from RACHEL server: http://rachelfriends.org/rachelusb_32EN/rachelusb_32EN_3.1.5.zip
Download from Labdoo FTP server: http://ftp.labdoo.org/download/RACHEL/RACHEL_EN.tar.gz

<strong>RACHEL in Spanish (actual version 1.0.0, ca. 25 GB)</strong>
Download from RACHEL server: http://rachelfriends.org/rachelusb_32ES/rachelusb_32ES_1.0.0.zip
Download from Labdoo FTP server: http://ftp.labdoo.org/download/RACHEL/RACHEL_ES.tar.gz

Having done that unzip the downloaded file in a new folder <code>/home/labdoo/Public/RACHEL</code> (might last a while..., please ignore the error message at the end). You will need the folder <code>/bin</code>, the the folder  <code>/www</code> and here in the file <code>/home/labdoo/Public/RACHEL/bin/www/starthere.html</code>, to be opened by double click in a web browser - and you should see the start page of RACHEL. The first block "wikipedia for schools" (Labdoo calls it wikidoo) is pre-installed on many Labdoo computers. So you should delete the complete folder  <code>/home/labdoo/Public/wikidoo</code>. This will give you back ca. 6,5 GB of disc capacity, otherwise it would be twice stored on this laptop.

To make access for users easier we recommend to pre-set a tab in the web browser (Firefox) to open the starthere-file. Open Firefox, often the first tab contains already "Wikipedia for Schools". Next open in the menu <code>File  --> Open File  --> navigate to /home/labdoo/Public/RACHEL/bin/www/starthere.html --> Open</code>.

Then <code>Edit --> Preferences , opens a window for the settings --></code>
<code>Click on "Use current Pages" --> close the tab "Preferences"</code>.

Please repeat these steps for the user <strong>labdoo</strong> and <strong>student</strong>.

<strong>Installation on a tablet</strong>
There is a installation file for Android (apk) http://rachelfriends.org/z-rachelandroid_APK/rachelandroid_APK_1.2.zip. But as long as you read the RACHEL content in a browser on a tablet, it is not necessary to install this apk-file. Just copy the RACHEL file to an Android- or Apple-tablet to use it. The drawback - most tablets have enough build-in RAM to store RACHEL. So you have to get external SD/microSD-Karten donated or buy it (if you tablet offers slots for RAM extension). But these RAM card are easily to be removed later... So you have to decide, if and how to install RACHEL on a tablet.

<strong>Remark:</strong>
RACHEL is much more than just content for a browser. With the download there are also coming e.g. exe-files for Windows, programs for Android or for a server. You will not need them for the Labdoo project, as we have a browser and the content installed on each computer. But these additional programs do not take much of the disc space, so just leave them where they are. So schools abroad can copy those tools and content to other platforms and use them.

For more information refer to the RACHEL domains in web:
Infos: http://www.worldpossible.org/rachel/
Online-Demo: http://www.rachel.worldpossible.org/</value>
</body>
<body>
<type>format</type>
<value>filtered_html_advanced</value>
</body>
<bid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>35</value>
</bid>
<plid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>819</value>
</plid>
<mlid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>1222</value>
</mlid>
<weight>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>-12</value>
</weight>
</book>
