<book>
<nid>
<type>node_id</type>
<value>199</value>
</nid>
<title>
<type>node_title</type>
<value>How To Start A Labdoo Laptop?</value>
</title>
<field_book_language>
<type>value</type>
<value>English</value>
</field_book_language>
<field_is_first_page>
<type>value</type>
<value>1</value>
</field_is_first_page>
<field_reference_book>
<type>target_id</type>
<value>199</value>
</field_reference_book>
<body>
<type>value</type>
<value><font color="red">
[Please print and attach this sheet to your dootronic shipment to ensure that the recipient knows how to use the computer. To print this sheet, click on 'Printer-friendly version' at the bottom of this page. Make sure to print it using the double page option in your printer settings to minimize the amount of paper used. Also, please print only one copy of this document for each group of laptops shipped together.]
</font>

<img src="/sites/default/files/content/wiki-de/edoovillages/login1.png" align="right" width="200" alt="Login Screen" />

<strong> User Accounts</strong>

Each laptop (cloned or installed using install-scripts) is preinstalled with 3 user accounts. When logging in click on the small triangle right from labdoo --> this will show you a list of currently available user accounts:

<ul>
<li><strong>labdoo</strong>: has super user rights / is administrator! The log-in password is <strong>labdoo</strong> (Please change this password when login for the first time. <strong>labdoo</strong> is an administrator account and have all the access right on the computer.  Working under this account without a proper knowledge may crash the system! Therefore, it is recommended to have only teachers know the password of the user <strong>labdoo</strong>)</li>

<li><strong>student</strong>: is a standard user  account for  students. The password is also <strong>labdoo</strong> (You can decide to change the current password or not.)</li>

<img src="/sites/default/files/content/wiki-de/edoovillages/login2.png" align="right" width="200" alt="Select user" />

<li><strong>guest</strong>: is an account which doesn’t  require a password to log in. All data will be automatically erased after the user log off from this account</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<br></br>
<table> 

<strong><caption>Other Log In Options</caption></strong>

<tr>
<th><img src="/sites/default/files/content/wiki-de/edoovillages/login3.png" width="150" alt=" " /></th>
<th><img src="/sites/default/files/content/wiki-de/edoovillages/login4.png" width="150" alt=" " /></th>
<th><img src="/sites/default/files/content/wiki-de/edoovillages/login5.png" width="150" alt=" " /></th>
</tr> 

<tr>
<td>Optional: select one of the pre-instaled desktops (user interface)</td>
<td><strong>Important! When typing in the password, make sure that the keyboard layout matches with your keyboard!</strong></td>
<td>Optional: Enlarge font size or improve contrast, if user is visually impaired</td>
</tr> 

</table>

<br></br>
</ul>

<strong>To change the password</strong> → System Tools → users and groups → +Add (to add a new user) or change → password „labdoo“ → change it → ok 

Manage Groups → to group users (e.g. group labdoo)

<strong>To Start a Program</strong>

There are many useful, fun and educational software and games installed. To start a program:

Click on the lower left corner on the Lubuntu icon (similar to Windows XP) → “Education” or "game“ → click on the program you want to start it.

In the folder of “/Public”, you will find a lot of useful reference manuals, such as OER, Offline wikis, e-books etc.

There are also a video tutorial and an Offline wikipedia (Xowa) icons available on the desktop.

<strong>Optional: Desktops (user interfaces)</strong>

Labdoo laptops come with Lubuntu (Linux operating system based on Ubuntu and the LXDE desktop). LXDE is a fast and easy to learn user interface. It can be installed on older laptops with minimum 256 / 512 MB RAM.

<img src="/sites/default/files/content/wikibook-the-labdoo-social-network-how-it-works/common/language_support.png" width="225" align="right"/>

You can also install different desktops as an option, but those may require more hardware resources.

<ul>
<li>Unity: minimum 1 GB of RAM</li>
<li>Gnome: minimum 756 MB - 1 GB of RAM</li>
</ul>

<strong>Please adjust languages, regional formats and keyboard settings when internet access is available.</strong>

Depending on the country edoovillage is located, you may want to install one or more additional language(s) or keyboard(s).

You can adjust language setting by selecting Preferences → Language Support. You may get messages like “Language support not completely installed, install now”. Click on "Yes" and continue the installation.

In the following windows, select Install/Remove languages → select the language(s) needed → Apply → Apply System-wide.

The new languages will show up in the language list (as shown above). Lubuntu will use the first language setting in the table, then go to the next one, and continue.  If no languages matched, it will use English as default.

<img src="/sites/default/files/content/wikibook-the-labdoo-social-network-how-it-works/common/regional_formats.png" width="225" align="right"/>

To change priority of the languages → select and hold the right mouse button on the new language  → move the language to its position and release the right mouse button → click Apply System-wide. The new language will be used after logout then login or after rebooting the computer.

<strong>Regional formats</strong>

You can also adjust the local currency, notation of numbers, date and time, if available. Click on the tab “Regional formats“ and select the format as shown in the list → Apply System-Wide. 

<strong>Keyboard settings</strong>

You may skip this step if the laptop was cloned with images. Otherwise, you have to add a panel item to the task bar by clicking with right mouse button on the task bar → Add / Remove Panel Items → +Add → select "Keyboard Layout Handler" → +Add → optional: move the item position within the task bar by Up or Down.

<img src="/sites/default/files/content/wikibook-the-labdoo-social-network-how-it-works/common/keyboard_layout_handler.png" width="225" align="right"/>

Right click on the symbol "de" (keyboard layout handler) in the task bar (or another country abbreviation will be shown) → Keyboard Layout handler Settings → Remove the hook "Keep system layout", if activated, otherwise, you won’t be able to add new layouts) →

+Add → Add a new keyboard layout
-Remove → Remove a  keyboard layout
^Up → Move a keyboard layout entry in the list up
vDown → Move a keyboard layout entry in the list up

The maximum number of  keyboard layouts is 4.. 

<strong>Manuals, video tutorials and more</strong>

<img src="/sites/default/files/content/wikibook-the-labdoo-social-network-how-it-works/common/link-folder-videos.png" align="right" width="50"/>

You can go to the folder <a href="file://localhost/home/labdoo/Public/">/home/labdoo/Public/</a>  for more manuals, video tutorials, offline wikis etc.  A tutorial video icon is placed on the desktop.  You can watch it by using Firefox or other media player (view -&gt; 1/2 size, zoom +/-).

Have fun learning and playing with your Labdoo laptop!

 The Labdoo team</value>
</body>
<body>
<type>format</type>
<value>filtered_html_advanced</value>
</body>
<bid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>142</value>
</bid>
<plid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>926</value>
</plid>
<mlid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>983</value>
</mlid>
<weight>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>0</value>
</weight>
</book>
