<book>
<nid>
<type>node_id</type>
<value>56</value>
</nid>
<title>
<type>node_title</type>
<value>Offline Access to the Labdoo Wiki</value>
</title>
<field_book_language>
<type>value</type>
<value>English</value>
</field_book_language>
<field_is_first_page>
<type>value</type>
<value>1</value>
</field_is_first_page>
<field_reference_book>
<type>target_id</type>
<value>56</value>
</field_reference_book>
<body>
<type>value</type>
<value>To download a wiki so that it can be accessed offline, you can use openly available tools that allow you to download a World Wide Web site from the Internet to a local directory. One tool that people have successfully used to download the Labdoo Wiki is called HTTrack, which is  available for free (under GPL, libre/free software license) from http://www.httrack.com/. 

This type of tools come very handy for instance when you want to include a certain wiki book into a laptop that you are going to bring to a school that may have limited Internet access. If you have any questions on how to use these tools, you can ask around in the <a href="/content/quality-assurance-qa">Quality Assurance team wall</a>. 

HTTrack documentation (overview) https://www.httrack.com/html/index.html
HTTrack how to use https://www.httrack.com/html/shelldoc.html (beginners)
HTTrack Manual https://www.httrack.com/html/fcguide.html (experts)

The Labdoo Team has collected and prepared for you these useful offline wikis:

https://www.labdoo.org/wiki-index
https://wiki.lxde.org/ 
https://wiki.ubuntu.com/
https://help.ubuntu.com/

These wikis will be updated each 1st day of a month and offered for download from our FTP server http://ftp.labdoo.org/download/Public/wikis/index.html (if you click this link a browser will open and you can surf through the offline wikis, but not download).

To download these offline wikis you have use our <a href="/content/cloning-laptops-using-prepared-labdoo-images">Labdoo images for cloning (wikis are already part of the images)</a> or you can use  <a href="/content/installation-scripts-overview">the installation script for content</a>.



</value>
</body>
<body>
<type>format</type>
<value>filtered_html_advanced</value>
</body>
<bid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>39</value>
</bid>
<plid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>826</value>
</plid>
<mlid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>840</value>
</mlid>
<weight>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>-7</value>
</weight>
</book>
