<book>
<nid>
<type>node_id</type>
<value>16743</value>
</nid>
<title>
<type>node_title</type>
<value>Alternatives to Linux</value>
</title>
<field_book_language>
<type>value</type>
<value>English</value>
</field_book_language>
<field_is_first_page>
<type>value</type>
<value>1</value>
</field_is_first_page>
<field_reference_book>
<type>target_id</type>
<value>16743</value>
</field_reference_book>
<body>
<type>value</type>
<value>There might be a need that edoovillages have to use another operating system (OS) beside Linux, e.g. Windows. If this is explained in advance it should be accepted, but the edoovillage should keep in mind that the OS is just a minor part, the important impact for the education comes from the educational software and content. So try to add as much as Open Educational Resources (OER) and free software as available for the OS.

If the laptop travels internationally, it is recommended to deliver the laptop with just a basic, licence free installation of (L)Ubuntu, and have the recipient side install the appropriate OS again. A basic OS is needed because international travel rules require laptops to be able to boot into an OS.

If the laptop does not travel internationally, it is recommended to deliver the laptop without OS. Just format the hard drive using 'shred'.

<strong>Whatever your decision to install an OS will be - do NOT offend any copyright or law. Only if the legal and license regulations for an OS are fulfilled (e.g. a valid license-key) you should install it. That is why Labdoo.org recommends open, license-free OS like (L)Ubuntu.</strong>

<strong>Virtualbox</strong>

If the Dootronic comes with min. 2 GB RAM and min. a dual CPU you can consider about using <a href="https://www.virtualbox.org/">Virtualbox</a>, a tool to install a guest OS (also called Virtual Machine (VM)). So you are able to use run e.g. (L)Ubuntu as the host OS and e.g. Windows as guest OS at the same time.

To install a VM you have to fulfil the same legal and license regulations as for a host OS.

The images for cloning come with a pre-installed Virtualbox already. And there is a installation script to install Virtualbox and its extensions for a Linux OS.</value>
</body>
<body>
<type>format</type>
<value>filtered_html_advanced</value>
</body>
<bid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>142</value>
</bid>
<plid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>926</value>
</plid>
<mlid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>1057</value>
</mlid>
<weight>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>-7</value>
</weight>
</book>
