<book>
<nid>
<type>node_id</type>
<value>172</value>
</nid>
<title>
<type>node_title</type>
<value>Obligation due to the receipient of a laptop donation</value>
</title>
<field_book_language>
<type>value</type>
<value>English</value>
</field_book_language>
<field_is_first_page>
<type>value</type>
<value>1</value>
</field_is_first_page>
<field_reference_book>
<type>target_id</type>
<value>172</value>
</field_reference_book>
<body>
<type>value</type>
<value><img src="/sites/default/files/content/labdoo-toolkit/labdoo-logos-education-1.png"  width="530"/>

Dear Laptop receiver:

We are very pleased to have the opportunity to contribute to your project by providing technology to help bridge the digital divide. 
With every right comes responsibilities. Technology, when adequately used, can provide very powerful means to aid those that are most in need. But if used improperly, it can also damage our environment. By receiving the above items, you are automatically accepting to abide by the following Labdoo global responsibilities:

(1) The items received will be used only for the purpose described by your organization at the time you solicited this donation. If you intend to use it for a different purpose, you will contact first the Labdoo team at contact@labdoo.org.

(2) In the case that an incidence occurs to any of the received items, you will contact the Labdoo team at contact@labdoo.org, including in your email the tagging number of the item(s) related to the incidence and a brief explanation. The following incidences must always be reported:
	(2.1) At the end of life of any of the received items, so that the item can be properly recycled. 
	(2.2) When an item breaks, malfunctions or any change in its status.

(3) Every six months, please send an email to contact@labdoo.org with the list of laptops that you have and their status (working or not working).

(4) Labdoo laptops are offered for free to you for education purposes.  In return, you agree to not use the laptops for commercial reasons and you agree not to charge any fee for the usage of the laptops. 

We thank you for your commitment to make our world a better place and we wish you best of luck in your humanitarian mission.

The Labdoo Team.
<img src="/profiles/labdoo/files/pictures/equation-2-alpha-smaller.png" width="80"/></value>
</body>
<body>
<type>format</type>
<value>filtered_html_advanced</value>
</body>
<bid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>142</value>
</bid>
<plid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>926</value>
</plid>
<mlid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>956</value>
</mlid>
<weight>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>0</value>
</weight>
</book>
