<book>
<nid>
<type>node_id</type>
<value>28535</value>
</nid>
<title>
<type>node_title</type>
<value>16.04 LTS does not boot, graphic resolution on screen low</value>
</title>
<field_book_language>
<type>value</type>
<value>English</value>
</field_book_language>
<field_is_first_page>
<type>value</type>
<value>1</value>
</field_is_first_page>
<field_reference_book>
<type>target_id</type>
<value>28535</value>
</field_reference_book>
<body>
<type>value</type>
<value>When you start (L)Ubuntu 16.04 LTS the first time in some cases it will not  boot correctly. Boot process will stop. But you will be able to start using the "Recovery Mode". In other cases the laptops starts, but the resolution on screen is very poor (often 640 x 480 pixel). Both can be solved (often):

<ul>
<li>Keep the Shift-button pressed when turning laptop on, press again after the BIOS messages shown, until the Grub menu is shown (GRUB controls the start process). You will also see the GRUB menu if power (I/O) is turned off during a start process.</li>

<li>Select "advanced options" and a Linux-Kernel and "Recovery-Start", just accept the next entries (press Enter) and log-in as labdoo user.</li>

<li>Open a terminal and type <code>sudo nano /etc/default/grub</code> (Enter). This will open the GRUB configuration file. If you are not familiar with the nano editor can use leafpad instead <code>sudo leafpad /etc/default/grub</code> (Enter)</li>

<li>Search the line <code># GRUB_GFXMODE=640x480</code> and remove "#" at the beginning of the line. Change the pre-set resolution of "640x480" in the setting you need for the graphic resolution. <strong>Important: you may only use a resolution supported by your video card!</strong> You can get the possible resolution(s) as follows using the (L)Ubuntu desktop or Parted Magic:</li>

<ul>
<li><strong>(L)Ubuntu Desktop:</strong> Menu, select Preferences → ARandR → Outputs → default → Resolution → will show available settings for resolution</li>

<li><strong>Parted Magic:</strong></li>
<ul>
<li> either Menu , select Desktop Settings → Screen Layout Editor → Outputs → LVDS1 → will show available settings for resolution or</li>
<li>System Profiler → Display → Resolution</li>
</ul>
</ul>

<li>Optional: in addition you may modify the line <code>GRUB_CMDLINE_LINUX_DEFAULT="quiet splash"</code> into <code>GRUB_CMDLINE_LINUX_DEFAULT="nomodeset splash"</code>. This will show you more details during boot procedure to check why and where the boot might stop.</li>

<li>Store all changes made in the editor and close editor.</li>

<li>Then open a terminal and type <code>sudo update-grub</code> (Enter). This will finally store the changes made within the GRUB configuration.</li>
</ul>

Having made these changes you have a good chance to start your laptops using (L)Ubuntu 16.04 LTS, showing a good resolution on screen.</value>
</body>
<body>
<type>format</type>
<value>filtered_html_advanced</value>
</body>
<bid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>35</value>
</bid>
<plid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>857</value>
</plid>
<mlid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>1570</value>
</mlid>
<weight>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>0</value>
</weight>
</book>
