<book>
<nid>
<type>node_id</type>
<value>156</value>
</nid>
<title>
<type>node_title</type>
<value>Link list of the images for cloning (FTP Server)</value>
</title>
<field_book_language>
<type>value</type>
<value>English</value>
</field_book_language>
<field_is_first_page>
<type>value</type>
<value>1</value>
</field_is_first_page>
<field_reference_book>
<type>target_id</type>
<value>156</value>
</field_reference_book>
<body>
<type>value</type>
<value>Actually there are these Labdoo images available on our FTP-Server http://ftp.labdoo.org/download/images/:

<strong>Lubuntu 14.04 LTS</strong>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://ftp.labdoo.org/download/images/PAE32_14_04_LTS.tar.gz">PAE32_14_04_LTS (Lubuntu 14.04 LTS for <strong>nonPAE and PAE 32 Bit CPU</strong>)</a></li>
<li><a href="http://ftp.labdoo.org/download/images/PAE64_14_04_LTS.tar.gz">PAE64_14_04_LTS (lubuntu 14.04 LTS for <strong>64 Bit CPU</strong>)</a></li>
</ul>
Double Click on the link of the needed image or right mouse click and "save as".

<strong>External disc or USB drive:</strong> Please make sure that your disc-drive, where you want to download the image to, is able to handle files larger 4 GB, e.g. <strong>NTFS</strong>. <strong>FAT32</strong> can handle files up to max. 4 GB, then the download will stop. Other disc formats like iOS, Linux may work, but not in combination with all laptops and operating systems. So we recommend NTFS as standard format.

<strong>Duration of download: </strong> The size of an Labdoo image is +/- 11 GB. If you use e.g. DSL 3000 it may last ca. 10 hours, DSL 6000 ca. 5 hours. But the download time may vary due to your provider, your internet connection, number of parallel downloads, bottle necks between the FTP server (Barcelona) and your place etc.

<strong>Please turn off power management circuits or sleep mode during the downloads, because otherwise the download could be interrupted.</strong>

14.04 tells you the release date of the Lubuntu release, e.g. 14.04 = April 2014. LTS (Long Term Support) releases will be supported and updated for 5 years, counted from this release date. The next LTS release will be released in April 2016 (16.04 LTS).</value>
</body>
<body>
<type>format</type>
<value>filtered_html_advanced</value>
</body>
<bid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>35</value>
</bid>
<plid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>900</value>
</plid>
<mlid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>940</value>
</mlid>
<weight>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>0</value>
</weight>
</book>
