<book>
<nid>
<type>node_id</type>
<value>16915</value>
</nid>
<title>
<type>node_title</type>
<value>Ideas to Work on with your Hub Members</value>
</title>
<field_book_language>
<type>value</type>
<value>English</value>
</field_book_language>
<field_is_first_page>
<type>value</type>
<value>1</value>
</field_is_first_page>
<field_reference_book>
<type>target_id</type>
<value>16915</value>
</field_reference_book>
<body>
<type>value</type>
<value>Here is a list of possible topics for the school hub to work on:

<ul>
<li><strong>Introduction to the Labdoo Project.</strong></li>

<ul>
<li>Help hub members get familiar with the Labdoo process (e.g., describe the <a href="../content/about-labdoo">state workflow S0 through S6</a>).</li>
<li>Get familiar with the Labdoo platform (e.g., <a href="../content/labdoo-social-network-how-it-works">Labdoo teams, the wiki system, etc.</a>).</li>
</ul>

<li><strong>Laptop Drives.</strong></li>

<ul>
<li>Reuse –  Discover idle laptops around you and put them into a better use.</li>
<li>Repurpose – An old laptop can have a new story. It can help provide education resources for underprivileged children.</li>
<li>Recycle –  By properly recycling a laptop, 41 lbs of carbon emission will be prevented from entering the atmosphere. This is equivalent to recycling 270 soda cans.</li>
<li> Spread awareness among  family and friends.</li>
<li> Set a goal on the number of laptops to be rescued for the semester.</li> 
<li> Plan a laptop drive campaign and design a flyer for it.</li> 
<li> Follow the link <a href="../content/labdoo-guide-rescue-laptop"> HERE </a> to learn how to effectively rescue an idle laptop.</li>
</ul>

<li><strong>Technical QA Session.</strong></li>

<ul>
<li>Learn how to build a Labdoo magic box (sanitizing a laptop).</li> 
<li>Join Labdoo Monthly meetings to learn how to fix a laptop.</li> 
<li>Examine basic laptop components together (e.g., memories, hard drives, etc.).</li>
</ul>

<li><strong>Dootrips.</strong></li>

<ul>
<li>Learn how the laptops get delivered without additional expenses.</li>
<li>Find traveling resources among family and friends.</li>
<li>Try to match existing trip plans with destinations to Edoovillages or other Labdoo hubs and ask travelers to help carry a laptop to its next stop.</li>
</ul>

<li><strong>Adopt a project site (Edoovillage).</strong></li>

<ul>
<li>Identify an organization which needs laptop resources.</li>
<li>Help manage communication between the edoovillage, dootripers, and hubs.</li>
</ul>

<li><strong>Be part of the software development team.</strong></li>

<ul>
<li>Help translate the Labdoo website into different languages.</li>
<li>Help proof-read the Labdoo website (wikipal).</li>
<li>Join the <a href="../content/source-code-development-team">Software Development Team Wall </a> and help test the Labdoo website, identify and report bugs.</li> 
<li>Get familiar with the programming language PHP and the Drupal System.</li>
<li>Sign up to <a href="https://github.com/Labdoo/Labdoo-2.0">Labdoo Github</a> and understand Labdoo framework.</li>
</ul>

<li><strong>Recycling.</strong></li>

<ul>
<li> Watch educational videos together (e.g., <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qoDcOqewX5c">TED Talks</a>).</li>
<li>Organize a field trip to recycling facility (e.g., <a href="http://www.allgreenrecycling.com/tustin/"> AllGreen Electronics Recycling, Tustin</a>).</li>
<li>Organize an e-waste drive.</li>
</ul>
</ul></value>
</body>
<body>
<type>format</type>
<value>filtered_html_advanced</value>
</body>
<bid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>34</value>
</bid>
<plid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>1062</value>
</plid>
<mlid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>1066</value>
</mlid>
<weight>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>0</value>
</weight>
</book>
