<book>
<nid>
<type>node_id</type>
<value>21504</value>
</nid>
<title>
<type>node_title</type>
<value>Managing Edoovillages</value>
</title>
<field_book_language>
<type>value</type>
<value>English</value>
</field_book_language>
<field_is_first_page>
<type>value</type>
<value>1</value>
</field_is_first_page>
<field_reference_book>
<type>target_id</type>
<value>21504</value>
</field_reference_book>
<body>
<type>value</type>
<value><strong>How to Create an Edoovillage</strong>

Labdoo users who have the "hub manager" role assigned are allowed to create new edoovillages. The process of creating a new Edoovillage is as follows:

<ol>
<li>
Fill in the 'Edoovillage Request Form'. You will find this form inside the <a href="../content/edoovillage-request-form">Labdoo Toolkit</a>. 
</li>

<li>
Click on the "Edoovillages" tab that you will find on the top bar of www.labdoo.org and then select the option "Create Edoovillage" (see Figure 1 below). Please notice that you will only see this option if your user account has the right permissions. If you don't see this option, send an email to contact@labdoo.org so we can assign the right permissions to your account. 
</li>

<li>
Using the information you collected from the 'Edoovillage Request Form', fill in all the fields in the form. Make sure to also upload the  'Edoovillage Request Form' in the field 'Project application'. Once you have filled in all the fields, click on the 'Save' button.
</li>
</ol>

<hr/>
<table align="center">
<tr><td>
<em> Figure 1. Click on "Edoovillages" and "Create" to start the creation of your edoovillage.</em>
</td></tr>
<tr><td>
<img src="/sites/default/files/content/wikibook-the-labdoo-social-network-how-it-works/edoovillage-form.png" width="800"/>
</td></tr>
</table>
<hr/>

Congratulations! At this point, your edoovillage is created and you are now one step closer to make a big contribution towards spreading education around the world. Please continue reading the next section for more pointers on how to manage your edoovillage.

<strong>Managing your Edoovillage Semaphore and Uploading Pictures</strong>

Each edoovillage comes with a semaphore which is displayed on the upper part of its dashboard (see Figure 2 below). The semaphore colors take the following meaning:

<ul>
<li>
Red. This is the initial state of an edoovillage. We need to ask recipients to send back pictures of the school. Until those pictures are not received, the semaphore is set to red and no laptops can be sent. Once the pictures of the school are received, the semaphore can be changed to orange.
</li>
<li>
Orange. This color means that pictures of the school have been received and a first batch of laptops can be sent. This usually means sending a few laptops (i.e., four or five laptops), but not all the laptops solicited. Once the first shipment of laptops is successfully received by the school, and once the school sends back more pictures of the received laptops demonstrating the correct reception, the color of the semaphore can be changed to green.
</li>
<li>
Green. This color means that the first batch of laptops was successfully received by the school and the school sent back pictures of the laptops. At this point, we are allowed to ship the rest of laptops solicited by the school.
</li>
</ul>

Two final remarks:

To change the status of your edoovillage semaphore, click on the 'Edit this edoovillage' link (see Figure 2) that you will find in your edoovillage dashboard (make sure you are logged in to see this link) and change the value of the field 'Semaphore'.

To upload the pictures you received from the school, click on the 'Go to photo album' button (see Figure 2).

<br/>
<hr/>
<table align="center">
<tr><td>
<em> Figure 2. On each edoovillage dashboard, you will see a semaphore drawing and a link to its photo album.</em>
</td></tr>
<tr><td>
<img src="/sites/default/files/content/wikibook-the-labdoo-social-network-how-it-works/edoovillage-semaphore-and-album.png" width="500"/>
</td></tr>
</table>
<hr/></value>
</body>
<body>
<type>format</type>
<value>filtered_html_advanced</value>
</body>
<bid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>39</value>
</bid>
<plid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>823</value>
</plid>
<mlid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>1236</value>
</mlid>
<weight>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>-2</value>
</weight>
</book>
