<book>
<nid>
<type>node_id</type>
<value>199</value>
</nid>
<title>
<type>node_title</type>
<value>How to start a laptop?</value>
</title>
<field_book_language>
<type>value</type>
<value>English</value>
</field_book_language>
<field_is_first_page>
<type>value</type>
<value>1</value>
</field_is_first_page>
<field_reference_book>
<type>target_id</type>
<value>199</value>
</field_reference_book>
<body>
<type>value</type>
<value><img src="/sites/default/files/content/wiki-de/edoovillages/login1.png" align="right" width="200" alt="Login Screen" />

<strong> User</strong>

Each laptop (cloned or installed using install-scripts) comes with 3 users. When logging in click on the small triangle right from labdoo --> this will show you a list of the available users:

<ul>
<li><strong>labdoo</strong>: has super user rights / is administrator! The log-in password is <strong>labdoo</strong> (Please change this password when logging in the first time, as the user <strong>labdoo</strong> is administrator and may destroy the system! So only teacher should know the password of the user labdoo)</li>

<li><strong>student</strong>: is the standard user for the students. His password is also <strong>labdoo</strong> (it's up to you, if you change the password for student)</li>

<img src="/sites/default/files/content/wiki-de/edoovillages/login2.png" align="right" width="200" alt="Select user" />

<li><strong>guest</strong>: needs no password, but all his entries will be aber es werden alle seine Eingaben und Änderungen nach der Abmeldung gelöscht</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<br></br>
<table> 

<strong><caption>More options when logging in</caption></strong>

<tr>
<th><img src="/sites/default/files/content/wiki-de/edoovillages/login3.png" width="150" alt=" " /></th>
<th><img src="/sites/default/files/content/wiki-de/edoovillages/login4.png" width="150" alt=" " /></th>
<th><img src="/sites/default/files/content/wiki-de/edoovillages/login5.png" width="150" alt=" " /></th>
</tr> 

<tr>
<td>Optional: select one of the pre-instaled desktops (user interface)</td>
<td><strong>Important! When typing the password make sure that the keyboard layout matches with your keyboard!</strong></td>
<td>Optional: Enlarge font size or improve contrast, if user is visually impaired</td>
</tr> 

</table>

<br></br>
</ul>

<strong>To change the password</strong> → System Tools → users and groups → +Add (to add a new user) or change → password „labdoo“ → change it → ok 

Manage Groups → to manage, if a user belongs to a certain group (e.g. group labdoo)

<strong>To start a program</strong>

Start e.g. using an educational program. There are a lot of interesting, funny and educational tools and games. And so you start:

Click in the left lower corner on the Lubuntu icon (similar to Windows XP) →  “Education” or „game“ → click on a program to start it

In the folder of „/Public“ you will find a lot of useful manuals, OER, Offline wikis, e-books etc. 

On the desktop you will a video tutorial and the Offline wiki tool Xowa. 

<strong>Optional: Desktops (user interfaces)</strong>

A Labdoo laptop comes with Lubuntu (Linux operating system based on Ubuntu and the LXDE desktop). LXDE is an easy to learn user interface, lean, fastl. LXDE / Lubuntu can be installed on older laptops, from 256 / 512 MB RAM.

<img src="/sites/default/files/content/wikibook-the-labdoo-social-network-how-it-works/common/language_support.png" width="225" align="right"/>

Optional you are able to install other desktops, but they ask for more hardware resources -

<ul>
<li>Unity: fast hardware needed (min 1 GB RAM)</li>
<li>Gnome: medium to fast hardware needed (756 MB - 1 GB RAM)</li>
</ul>

<strong>language, regional formats and keyboard settings (please adjust when online)</strong>

Depending on the country of the edoovillage you may want to install one or more additional language(s) or keyboard(s).

Click Preferences → Language Support. Sometimes you get the message “Language support not completely installed, install now” → confirm by "Yes" and install.

In the next window click → Install/Remove languages → select the language(s) needed → Apply → Apply System-wide.

The new languages will show up in the language list above: Lubuntu first tries to find a word in this table in language no. 1, next in language no. 2 and so on, and will stop using English.

<img src="/sites/default/files/content/wikibook-the-labdoo-social-network-how-it-works/common/regional_formats.png" width="225" align="right"/>

To change priority of the languages → mark the new language → right mouse click on new language, keep on pressing right mouse button → move the language to its position, drop it → click  Apply System-wide. The new language will be used after logout and login or reboot of the computer.

<strong>Regional formats</strong>

You can also adjust the local currency, notation of numbers, date and time (if available). Click tab „Regional formats“ and select format in the list shown → Apply System-Wide. 

<strong>keyboard settings</strong>

If the laptop was cloned using images you can go ahead. Otherwise you have to add a panel item to the task bar → right mouse click on the task bar → Add / Remove Panel Items → +Add → select "Keyboard Layout Handler" → +Add → optional: move the item position within the task bar by Up or Down.

<img src="/sites/default/files/content/wikibook-the-labdoo-social-network-how-it-works/common/keyboard_layout_handler.png" width="225" align="right"/>

Right mouse click on the symbol "de" (keyboard layout handler) in the task bar (or another country abreviation shown) → Keyboard Layout handler Settings → Remove the hook "Keep system layout", if activated (otherwise you are not able to add new layouts) → 

+Add → Add a new keyboard layout
-Remove → Remove a  keyboard layout
up → Move a keyboard layout entry in the list up
down → Move a keyboard layout entry in the list up

The number of keyboard layout entries is limited to 4 (four). 

<strong>Manuals, video tutorials and more</strong>

<img src="/sites/default/files/content/wikibook-the-labdoo-social-network-how-it-works/common/link-folder-videos.png" align="right" width="50"/>

For manuals, video tutorials, offline wikis etc. open the folder <a href="file://localhost/home/labdoo/Public/">/home/labdoo/Public/</a>. Or click on the icon "videos" on the desktop to open the video tutorials folder. A video can be watched using Firefox or a player (view -&gt; 1/2 size, zoom +/-).

Have fun learning and playing with your Labdoo laptop! The Labdoo team</value>
</body>
<body>
<type>format</type>
<value>filtered_html_advanced</value>
</body>
<bid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>142</value>
</bid>
<plid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>926</value>
</plid>
<mlid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>983</value>
</mlid>
<weight>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>0</value>
</weight>
</book>
