<book>
<nid>
<type>node_id</type>
<value>94</value>
</nid>
<title>
<type>node_title</type>
<value>No need for funding, just collaboration and excess capacity</value>
</title>
<field_book_language>
<type>value</type>
<value>English</value>
</field_book_language>
<field_is_first_page>
<type>value</type>
<value>1</value>
</field_is_first_page>
<field_reference_book>
<type>target_id</type>
<value>94</value>
</field_reference_book>
<body>
<type>value</type>
<value>Labdoo runs without investors or any source of funding. The founders decided to take this approach because of several reasons:

<ul>
<li>
To run Labdoo, there is no need for money.  The world has so much excess capacity (laptops, travelers, connectivity, goodwill, etc), that we have the capability to solve the digital divide problem without incurring any additional cost (economic or environmental).
</li>
<li>
By removing the money factor, the project's mission becomes clean and focused.  This approach implies that there is no possible confusion on what the objective of the project is and it strengthens its values. The only possible motivation supporting the project is one of making a contribution to the global community.
</li>
<li>
This approach makes Project Labdoo resilient against global economic crisis. A paradox about our economic system is that when there is an economic crisis, social projects are the ones who get the biggest hits in terms of budget cuts. Hence, those that need the biggest help are the ones who get hit first and harder. This is so because of the money-dependency factor in practically all social projects. By removing the money from the equation, Labdoo can continue to operate normally even in the presence of economic recessions. In fact, Project Labdoo was created in the midst of one of the biggest economic recessions of the last 100 years. 
</li>
<li>
The opportunity cost. If we invest $1000 in bringing one laptop to a needy school, automatically we are des-investing $1000 from all other humanitarian projects such as the provision of health care, clean water, shelter, etc. Let's use the money for those projects that really need it.
</li>
<li>
It substantially simplifies the paperwork and the logistics of international cooperation.
</li>
<li>
It allows for exploring new and more sustainable ways to organize global communities toward solving global problems.  
</li>
</ul>
</value>
</body>
<body>
<type>format</type>
<value>filtered_html_advanced</value>
</body>
<bid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>80</value>
</bid>
<plid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>821</value>
</plid>
<mlid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>835</value>
</mlid>
<weight>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>-12</value>
</weight>
</book>
