<book>
<nid>
<type>node_id</type>
<value>108</value>
</nid>
<title>
<type>node_title</type>
<value>Creating New Hubs</value>
</title>
<field_book_language>
<type>value</type>
<value>English</value>
</field_book_language>
<field_is_first_page>
<type>value</type>
<value>1</value>
</field_is_first_page>
<field_reference_book>
<type>target_id</type>
<value>108</value>
</field_reference_book>
<body>
<type>value</type>
<value>Labdoo users who have the "superhub" role assigned are allowed to create new Labdoo hubs. (For information on what a hub is, please refer to the <a href="/content/hubs">Hubs Section</a> in the 'Values and Principles' wiki book.) The process of creating a new Labdoo hub is as follows:

<ul>
<li>
<strong>Intial contact.</strong> The group soliciting to create a hub contacts Labdoo. This can be done through different ways, including getting in touch with an existing neighbor hub or by directly emailing contact@labdoo.org. Such request is propagated to the Labdoo superhub in charge of the region where the new hub is to be created.
</li>
<li>
<strong>Explaining what a Labdoo hub is.</strong> The superhub explains the potential hub manager candidates how a Labdoo hub works. It is recommended to do such communication using a phone call (can be a regular or Internet-based phone call) to ensure a proper conversation.
</li>
<li>
<strong>Creation of Labdoo user accounts.</strong> Once decided that the hub is to be created, if the candidates don't have a Labdo user account yet, they need to create one for each of the users that will be managing the hub by going to https://www.labdoo.org/user/register.
</li>
<li>
<strong>Creation of the hub.</strong> The superhub creates the new hub by going to the <a href="/node/add/hub">create hub page</a> (this page is available only to users who have superhub rights and it can be found under the 'Hub' tab in the <a href="/content/main-navigation-menu-mnm">'Main Navigation Menu'</a>) and filling in all the necessary information. Make sure to include all the users in charge of managing the new hub in the field ''Hub manager(s)' in this form.
</li>
<li>
<strong>Assigning roles.</strong> In the last step, the users in charge of managing the hub need to be given the additional role of 'hub manager'. To do this, go to each user page <code>https://www.labdoo-dev.org/users/USERNAME</code> (where USERNAME is the username of the user), click on the tab 'Roles', and activate the checkbox 'hub manager' as illustrated in the next figure.
<hr/>
<em> Figure. To assign the 'hub manager' role, go to that user's page, click on 'Roles' and select the appropriate checkbox.</em>
<img src="/sites/default/files/content/wikibook-the-labdoo-social-network-how-it-works/assign-role.png"/>
<hr/>
</li>
</ul>

After the above steps, the new hub managers can start their hub activities as described in the <a href="/content/managing-hubs">Hubs Section</a> of this wiki book.
</value>
</body>
<body>
<type>format</type>
<value>filtered_html_advanced</value>
</body>
<bid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>75</value>
</bid>
<plid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>813</value>
</plid>
<mlid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>820</value>
</mlid>
<weight>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>-15</value>
</weight>
</book>
