<book>
<nid>
<type>node_id</type>
<value>96</value>
</nid>
<title>
<type>node_title</type>
<value>Hubs</value>
</title>
<field_book_language>
<type>value</type>
<value>English</value>
</field_book_language>
<field_is_first_page>
<type>value</type>
<value>1</value>
</field_is_first_page>
<field_reference_book>
<type>target_id</type>
<value>96</value>
</field_reference_book>
<body>
<type>value</type>
<value>Everybody can be a participatnt in the Labdoo network by performing a Labdoo activity.  When one or more of the participants act together regularly carrying out a good number of activities, they can optionally become a hub.  A hub can be understood as a node in the network which carries out a “larger density of Labdoo activities”.  Examples of hubs can be a group of students in a university that get together from time to time to carry activities such as collecting and sanitizing unused laptops, organizing dootrips, recycling technology, carrying out outreaching activities, etc.  Hubs can also be implemented in high schools, companies, neighbor communities, at home or in any type of organized community.

When a hub is created, it receives a kit containing the following:

<ul>
<li>
A hub space inside the Labdoo systems that allows for the management of donated devices, dootrips, edoovillages, etc.
</li>
<li>
The listing of the hub in the page www.labdoo.org/hubs to help it gain visiblity.
</li>
<li>
The rights to create new edoovillages.
</li>
<li>
A web album inside the hub space where pictures of the hub's activities can be uploaded.
</li>
</ul>
If a hub becomes inactive for at least six months or if it acts against the Labdoo principles described in this charter, its kit can be removed or reassigned to another hub or group of people.</value>
</body>
<body>
<type>format</type>
<value>filtered_html_advanced</value>
</body>
<bid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>72</value>
</bid>
<plid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>785</value>
</plid>
<mlid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>793</value>
</mlid>
<weight>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>-14</value>
</weight>
</book>
