<book>
<nid>
<type>node_id</type>
<value>83</value>
</nid>
<title>
<type>node_title</type>
<value>Laptop Sanitation Manual</value>
</title>
<field_book_language>
<type>value</type>
<value>English</value>
</field_book_language>
<field_is_first_page>
<type>value</type>
<value>1</value>
</field_is_first_page>
<field_reference_book>
<type>target_id</type>
<value>83</value>
</field_reference_book>
<body>
<type>value</type>
<value><strong>About this document</strong>

This brief document describes the process of (1) collecting unused laptops from your local community, (2) sanitizing and (3) packaging them to make them ready for traveling to a needy school. This document can be used by Labdooers working as individuals (from home, from work, from your local organizations), or groups of Labdooers working as part of a Labdoo hub.

If in any of these steps you get stuck, you can use the <a href='/content/quality-assurance-qa'>Labdoo QA Team</a> to find answers to your questions or to ask new ones.

<strong>Collecting laptops from your local community</strong>

There exist several strategies to collect unused laptops from your local community, but in all of them, the main idea is to outreach to your network of friends, relatives, coworkers, classmates, etc. to help bring awareness about your laptop drive activities. Many of the people you know have unused laptops sitting idle and the objective is to give them an option to repurpose their unused laptops for a humanitarian/education cause. Some ideas to help you collect laptops are:

<ul>
<li>
If you are a student or a teacher in a school, you can write a letter to the parents of the students asking for unused laptops. Many parents work for companies who have unused laptops.
</li>
<li>
Use your social network skills and tools to bring awareness. Write a post on your favorite social networks (Facebook, Twitter, Google Plus, etc.) letting people know about your laptop collection activities.
</li>
<li>
You can also be creative and come up with your laptop collection strategy. You will find tools to help organize your local campaigns inside the <a href='/sites/default/files/content/labdoo-tolkit/packaging.png'>Labdoo Toolkit</a>.
</li>
</ul>

<strong>Sanitizing the laptops</strong>

Once you have laptops, organize a laptop sanitation event. You can invite your friends at home, at school, at work, etc. and spend a couple of hours or so sanitizing laptops, or you can do it on your own too. The current standard process of sanitizing a laptop is as follows:

<ol>
<li>
Start by tagging your laptop by going to the <a href="/node/add/laptop">tagging page</a>. Make sure you print the three labels and attach two of them to the laptop and one to the AC adapter following the instructions that you will find in the website.
</li>
<li>
Download the Lubuntu 14.04 release from this link (this is a large .iso image):
http://cdimage.ubuntu.com/lubuntu/releases/14.04/release/lubuntu-14.04-desktop-i386.iso
</li>
<li>
Burn the downloaded file into a CD. 
</li>
<li>
Introduce the CD into the laptop you intend to sanitize.
</li>
<li>
Upon booting the laptop with the CD, you should see the Linux installation menu. If you don't see it, you need to enter into the bios of the laptop and change the booting order of your computer to make sure it first boots from the CD. 
</li>
<li>
Upon seeing the Linux installation menu, start by selecting the installation language; for instance, choose “English”.
</li>
<li>
Select “Install Lubuntu”.
</li>
<li>
Select the language to be installed in the laptop. If you don't know the destination country,  select “English”. If you know the destination country, select that country's language.
</li>
<li>
Select the destination country. If you don't know it, pick any country that you like.
</li>
<li>
Where it says “detect keyboard”, say “No”.
</li>
<li>
In the next screen, pick the country of origin of your keyboard.
</li>
<li>
When it tries to configure the network, press “cancel” (there is no need to do network installation since you have the CD and the updates are installed later).
</li>
<li>
When it asks for the “hostname”, please enter the word “labdoo”.
</li>
<li>
When it asks for the “fullname”, please enter the word “labdoo”.
</li>
<li>
When it asks for the “username”, please enter the word “labdoo”.
</li>
<li>
When it asks for the “password”, please enter the word “labdoo”.
</li>
<li>
When it says “Use weak password?”, please say “Yes”.
</li>
<li>
When it says “Encrypt your home directory?”, please say “No”.
</li>
<li>
Select any time zone you want if the system asks you.
</li>
<li>
When it says “Partitioning method”, please say “Guided – use entire disk”.
</li>
<li>
Select the only hard drive available in your laptop.
</li>
<li>
When it says “Write changes to disks”, please say “Yes”.
At this point the installation will start. There are two more questions that will come up during the installation:
</li>
<li>
When asked for HTTP proxy information, please leave it empty and just press “Continue”.
</li>
<li>
When it says “Install the GRUB boot loader”, please say “Yes”.
</li>
<li>
When it says “Is the system clock set to UTC”, please say “Yes”.
This completes the installation of the basic operating system. Next, reboot the machine and log into the Lubuntu system using the username “labdoo and password “labdoo”. Once you are into the Lubuntu system, Make sure also that the laptop is connected to the Internet, via Ethernet cable or via WIFI. Finally, type ALT+CTRL+t to open a terminal window, and in it, type the following commands:

<code>$ sudo apt-get update [and press ENTER]</code>
<code>$ sudo apt-get install edubuntu-desktop libreoffice [and press ENTER]</code>
<code>$ sudo apt-get upgrade [and press ENTER]</code>
The last two commands could take from a few minutes up to an hour or so to complete.
</li>
</ol>

<strong>Packaging the laptops ready for traveling</strong>

Once a laptop has been sanitized following the steps in Section II, we need to package it so it can travel to a destination school. The main goals of the packaging are two-fold: (1) the packaging should protect the laptop from any possible rough traveling conditions; (2) the packaging should make visible the Labdoo identifier of the laptop, for both its AC adapter and the laptop itself. A recommended approach is to use transparent, bubble plastic wrap and to tape the Labdoo identifier in big letters outside, for both the laptop and its AC adapter, as shown in the following pictures:

<hr></hr>
<em> Figure. A good way to pack your doojects: use a wrapping material to properly protect them and write the Labdoo IDs clearly outside both the devices and the AC adapters.</em>
<img src="/sites/default/files/content/labdoo-toolkit/packaging.png"/>
<hr></hr>

You are welcome to use other packaging approaches based on what's available to you, as long as the laptop is well protected and its Labdoo identifier is made visible externally.

<strong>What to expect next</strong>

Congratulations! You have now successfully completed your laptop drive campaign and sanitized/packaged your laptops, so they are now ready to travel. At this point, the recommended next steps are as follows:

<ul>
<li>
If you are traveling yourself to a school project, you can bring the laptops in your luggage. Try to distribute as many laptops to as many people traveling with you as possible because some countries have a limit on the amount of laptops that can be carried per person.
</li>
<li>
If you are not traveling, then get in touch with one of the Labdoo hubs (for instance, one which is closest to you) from the <a href="/hubs">hubs list</a>. The Labdoo hub will help you decide which school your laptop should be sent to and it will also help you get in touch with the travelers going to that school so the laptops can be picked up from you.
</li>
</ul></value>
</body>
<body>
<type>format</type>
<value>filtered_html_advanced</value>
</body>
<bid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>81</value>
</bid>
<plid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>751</value>
</plid>
<mlid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>752</value>
</mlid>
<weight>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>-15</value>
</weight>
</book>
