<book>
<nid>
<type>node_id</type>
<value>74</value>
</nid>
<title>
<type>node_title</type>
<value>What is Labdoo and why does Labdoo exist?</value>
</title>
<field_book_language>
<type>value</type>
<value>English</value>
</field_book_language>
<field_is_first_page>
<type>value</type>
<value>1</value>
</field_is_first_page>
<field_reference_book>
<type>target_id</type>
<value>74</value>
</field_reference_book>
<body>
<type>value</type>
<value>Labdoo is a collaborative humanitarian social network which is designed to help bring laptops and educational devices to schools in need without incurring any economic or environmental costs.

In the world, those who have access to free sources of education (FSE) are the rare exception.  As much as 5 billion people (5 out of 7 persons in the world) don't have access to FSE. This is a problem at least for two reasons:

<ol>
<li>
It leads to an ever increasing inequality gap between those who have access to FSE and those who don't.  
</li>
<li>
The potential talent of most of the children in the world and the global benefits that would arise from it are lost.
</li>
</ol>

This reality is commonly known as the <em>'digital divide'</em>.

A laptop allows schools to gain access to FSE, helping to unlock the skills and potential capabilities of children and students. This can be achieved via online education content or, in those places where Internet is not available yet, via offline education software that comes installed in the laptops.

Labdoo exists as 'a tool' to help sustainably coordinate the mobilization of unused educational devices to bring them to needy schools using global collaboration and without incurring any economic or environmental cost. It is designed so that everyone who has an unused laptop (at home, in the school/university, at work or anywhere) can participate. 

Imagine if the 2 billion people who do have access to FSE spend just one hour of our time to bring our unused laptops and tablets to needy children around the world. That's all it takes to enable universal access to free sources of education, and it can be done while preserving Planet Earth too.
</value>
</body>
<body>
<type>format</type>
<value>filtered_html_advanced</value>
</body>
<bid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>72</value>
</bid>
<plid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>767</value>
</plid>
<mlid>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>769</value>
</mlid>
<weight>
<type>book_array</type>
<value>-15</value>
</weight>
</book>
